<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The morning ramble, or, The town-humours a comedy acted at the Duke's Theatre.</title>
            <author>Payne, Henry Neville, fl. 1672-1710.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1673</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 195 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 41 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A56734</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P892</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R11211</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13790835</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13790835</idno>
            <idno type="VID">101839</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A56734)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 101839)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 470:19)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The morning ramble, or, The town-humours a comedy acted at the Duke's Theatre.</title>
                  <author>Payne, Henry Neville, fl. 1672-1710.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 74, [2] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Thomas Dring ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1673.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Attributed to Henry Payne.  Cf. Halkett &amp; Laing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:101839:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:101839:1"/>
            <p>THE Morning Ramble, OR, THE TOWN-HUMOURS: A COMEDY.</p>
            <p>Acted at the Duke's Theatre.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Thomas Dring,</hi> at the <hi>White Lyon,</hi> next <hi>Chancery-Lane</hi> end in <hi>Fleet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreet.</hi> 1673.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="prologue">
            <pb facs="tcp:101839:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:101839:2"/>
            <head>PROLOGUE.</head>
            <l>CRiticks, now boaſt your power, for you have made</l>
            <l>A Tragick muſe run mad in maſquerade.</l>
            <l>All Poets before him the Laws did ſlight</l>
            <l>Of ſuch as only rail'd, but could not Write.</l>
            <l>But he ſubmits ſo far, that you will ſwear</l>
            <l>His firſt was writ in blood, but this i'th' Air.</l>
            <l>'Twas nine day's work: but truly there might be</l>
            <l>As good a Play juſt ſpoke <hi>Ex tempore.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>For Whip and Spur, 'tis <hi>A-la-mode de France;</hi>
            </l>
            <l>A thing made up of Fiddle, Song, and Dance.</l>
            <l>All three your dear Delights, no matter then</l>
            <l>Whether of ſence there be one line in ten:</l>
            <l>This Age is not for that, 'tis much too wiſe,</l>
            <l>VVhat Poets teach, you dull moralities;</l>
            <l>That was their buſineſs in that humble Age,</l>
            <l>VVhen Hedges were their Scenes, and Fields their Stage,</l>
            <l>VVhen the poor ſimple VVorld ſtrove to be good;</l>
            <l>Thank time, things now are better underſtood.</l>
            <l>But yet he could not leave, you'l ſee him now</l>
            <l>Have a ſlight paſs or two at ſome of you;</l>
            <l>He thinks there's Bullys dare not fight, i'th' Pit</l>
            <l>As well as Criticks, that he's ſure want wit.</l>
            <l>One may be both — They that make moſt ado,</l>
            <l>Do oftneſt want both wit and courage too.</l>
            <l>But fear no common place, nor ſober ſaws,</l>
            <l>By ſome late Plays he partly knows your Laws.</l>
            <l>At a quaint Dance, or a Grimace that takes,</l>
            <l>The Theatre with loud applauſes ſhakes.</l>
            <l>But if true thought be with good Language dreſt,</l>
            <l>You ſlightly cry, 'twas well enough expreſt.</l>
            <l>Then as you've us'd ſome Plays, ſo do by this,</l>
            <l>Clap but that part which wild and ſenſeleſs is,</l>
            <l>And for what's wiſe we give you leave to hiſs.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="dramatis_personae">
            <pb facs="tcp:101839:3"/>
            <head>The Actors Names.</head>
            <list>
               <item>Townlove.</item>
               <item>Merry.</item>
               <item>Ruffle.</item>
               <item>Muchland.</item>
               <item>Raſh.</item>
               <item>Fullam.</item>
               <item>Breef.</item>
               <item>Conſtable.</item>
               <item>Drawer.</item>
               <item>Officers.</item>
               <item>Souldiers <hi>and</hi> Watchmen.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. Betterton.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. Harris.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. Smith.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. Medbourn.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. Crosby.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nderhill.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. Norris.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <item>Honour Muchland.</item>
               <item>Betty Raſh.</item>
               <item>Roſe.</item>
               <item>Lady Turnup.</item>
               <item>Two Maid-Servants.</item>
               <item>Three Vizard-Masks.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mrs. Johnſon.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mrs. Long.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mrs. Shadwell.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mrs. Osborn.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="play">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:101839:3"/>
            <head>THE Morning Ramble.</head>
            <div n="1" type="act">
               <head>The Firſt Act.</head>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Townlove <hi>and</hi> Merry, <hi>with Fiddles and Torches.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">N</seg>O drawing back, <hi>Townlove,</hi> I'm engag'd, and am reſolv'd to make a Night on't.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Townl.</speaker>
                  <p>Prethee, <hi>Will Merry,</hi> let's part; thou know'ſt I never uſe that word to thee but when I have extraordinary bus'neſs.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Bus'neſs! what bus'neſs canſt thou have? I'le warrant you you're to be up betimes it'h Morning to ſell a parcel of fat Sheep or Oxen, new come from your Eſtate in the Countrey, or elſe to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruct Counſel in a Cauſe of yours depending I know not where. Bus'neſs, quoth a, that ever a well-bred Gentleman ſhould ſuffer the word to come into his Mouth.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Townl.</speaker>
                  <p>I tell thee, <hi>Will,</hi> I have bus'neſs, ſerious bus'neſs, and bus'neſs fit for a Gentleman; let that ſatisfie you: and ſo farewell.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Stay, Stay, this ſhan'not do, <hi>Townlove,</hi> I ſmell you out; You fear I'le carry you to ſome lewd Houſe now that abounds in <hi>Burgundy,</hi> and there top up with 'tother half dozen Bottles; then the dreadful Head-ake comes and keeps you in two dayes to be the diſappointment of Lord knows how many ſhe-friends.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Townl.</speaker>
                  <p>And do you think ſuch fears are not very reaſonable? A Man indeed hath ſo much time allow'd him in this World, that he ſhould neglect the Living two dayes for the delight of two hours: Prethee think, would any Man of ſenſe part with his time at that rate?</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:101839:4"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, <hi>Townlove,</hi> thou art mad, diſtracted, gone, and I'm afraid, beyond recovery; thou can'ſt not conſider things I ſee.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Townl.</speaker>
                  <p>If want of conſideration be a ſign of madneſs, <hi>Will,</hi> thou haſt been a little craz'd ever ſince I knew thee. But prethee, what han't I conſider'd in this matter?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Living, <hi>Townlove,</hi> Living: thou haſt not ſo much as con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider'd what bus'neſs thou was ſent into the World about — Tis Living, Man.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, I know 'tis Living, and therefore I ſtrive to Live as much of the time I have allow'd me as I can.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Thou Live, and yet ſpeak againſt Drinking, the very thing that diſtinguiſhes the Life of Man from that of a Beaſt! Why, 'tis the onely Spur of Wit and Reaſon; I have heard more new thoughts in Drinking three hours, then the beſt Modern Play can furniſh you with; Therefore if thou would'ſt Live, that is, truly enjoy thy ſelf, Drink, I ſay, Drink.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, I can neither ſtay to do it, nor talk of it now; and therefore good bu'y.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay, faith, thou ſhalt ſtay till I give a ſerenade to my Miſtreſs now, I am under the Window; ſtrike up, Boyes.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Hold; ſure <hi>Will,</hi> thou'rt mad — Doſt not know her Brother is a ſerious Gentleman, and not us'd to City frolicks; 'tis the only way to loſe her for ever.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, this 'tis, not to underſtand Drinking, it makes one as dull and thoughtleſs as a Countrey Curate, that lives upon ſix pounds, and a caſt Caſſock two and fifty Sundayes; doſt thou think I would Marry her, if I did not intend to reclaim both her and her Brother from dull ſobriety.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, thou wouldeſt not have thy Wife Drink, woud'ſt thou?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>No, but I would have her be as mad, and love thoſe that do, Women are fine thin things, the breath of a Man that is merry is ſufficient to inſpire them with wit enough for a Woman, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore here I declare that I will ſerenade her, and if ſhe ſhews the leaſt diſlike to the frolick, I will, in ſpight of Love and all his little tricks, diſclaim her for ever. And therefore, Boyes, to our bus'neſs; come, the Song I made.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:101839:4"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, I'le ſtay to ſee thee a poor diſcarded, melancholy, diſconſolate Lover, and then I'le leave thee, and go to my Miſtreſs.</p>
                  <q>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                        <body>
                           <div type="song">
                              <head>Song.</head>
                              <l>FRom Friends juſt inſpir'd with brisk <hi>Burgundy</hi> Wine,</l>
                              <l>Speaking raptures of Reaſon, and ſayings Divine.</l>
                              <l>I come — I come — from this Heav'n I come,</l>
                              <l>And through dirt and darkneſs I willingly roam,</l>
                              <l>To follow a Boy that confeſſes he's blind,</l>
                              <l>He tells me of hope, but leads me through fear,</l>
                              <l>Nay, ſometimes I'm juſt on the brink of deſpair;</l>
                              <l>Yet on I follow, I follow ſtill, leaving behind</l>
                              <l>The two mighty Bleſſings, my Bottle and Friend.</l>
                              <l>He tells me of Bliſs,</l>
                              <l>Beyond this,</l>
                              <l>Yet will not declare where my Journey ſhall end.</l>
                              <stage>Chorus.</stage>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Ah, what Charms have thoſe Eyes!</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>That a Love ſo ſtrong can inſpire,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>It Mirth, Wit, and Friendſhip defies,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>And Wine cannot ſlacken its fire.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Then ſpight of my ſelf I muſt follow him ſtill,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>A Devil, or a God, let him be which he will,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>I cannot, nay, would not retire,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>No, though I were ſure to be burnt in the fire.</hi>
                              </l>
                           </div>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                  </q>
                  <stage>Roſe <hi>appears in a Night-Gown above.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>For Heav'ns ſake, Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> be gone; my Miſtreſs knows who you are, but ſhould her Brother do ſo, we ſhould be ſent into the Countrey immediately.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Roſe, Roſe,</hi> I tell thee, <hi>Roſe,</hi> I would follow with this noiſe of Fiddles at my heels, and drive him back to Town, or never let him ſleep but in ſhelter of as many Night-Caps as <hi>Moroſe</hi> in the Silent Woman hath.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I am very ſerious, Sir, my Lady begs you to be gone before you wake her Brother.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, <hi>Roſe,</hi> confeſs, confeſs; I know thou art acquainted with a touch of thy Miſtreſſes ſecrets: Tell me, is there no other
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:101839:5"/>ſeat but of being ſent into the Countrey?</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Honour, Muchland <hi>appears.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Oh, yes, no doubt on't, the Miſtreſs is highly concern'd for fear of loſing the hopes of ſo ſober a Husband.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Marry, and I thought ſo. —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>One, that if a Body has occaſion for at night may be heard of either in a Tavern, French-houſe, Conſtables hands, or the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Well; and is not that better then to be troubl'd with a formal fopp of bus'neſs, who lodges his wife in the Countrey, to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe for the Agne, then ſcratches his empty Noddle, cryes, I proteſt I muſt poſt to <hi>London,</hi> I ſhall be undone elſe; there ſtayes a whole Term a doing nothing, or what is as bad, that which comes at laſt to nothing.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Townl.</speaker>
                  <p>And thinks he performs his Duty very well to his Wife, if he gives her a bout every poſt with a long formal Letter of Excuſes for not coming.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>VVhich muſt beget another on her full of Complaints, for his abſence.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Then when he returns in the Spirit of Beef and Ale, <hi>Will,</hi> it may beget a Male Child.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Which proves like the Ingredients 'tis Compounded of, a fit Companion for Clowns, and of no uſe but to have his Name in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerted in long Indentures, Tripartite for Intaling, ſpecially that Earth that is near as ſenſible as it's Clod-pate owner.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>The drawing of this deed too is a new excuſe for coming to <hi>London,</hi> and ſeeing, as the learned have it, his Uncle.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>So, that in fine your man of bus'neſs loves to be thought to love bus'neſs, Courts bus'neſs, lyes with bus'neſs, and begets no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but buſineſs, or things as dull as buſineſs; and, Lady, will you ſlight a Man that loves Wit, Mirth, and <hi>Burgundy,</hi> for this Animal, non<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rationale.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>I pray, Sir, where's the neceſſity for marrying either, do you think there is none but ſuch as cannot ſtay at home for their bus'neſs, or will not, for their Wine and Wenches?</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:101839:5"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Lady, have a care; that is my Province: Wenches! if you ſpeak irreverently of Wenches I am bound to ſtand up for them, and ſhall ſoon be provok't to ſay, that if my friend here, and ſome few others like him, could but reliſh the pleaſure of Wenching, you, and all the ill-bred honeſt Women in the Town might ſleep quietly, or waking, gnaw your Sheets without the help of a Song and Fiddle at your windows. VVenching, quoth a.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> I ſee you, for your Wine, and your Friend for Wenches, are ſo well met, 'twould be pity to part you, and I am reſolv'd not to be ſo cruel; therefore aſſuring you I am not in haſt for a Husband, but can ſtay till a ſoberer grow; if there be none yet ripe, I leave you to your further Adventures.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exiturus</hi> Honour <hi>and</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, no parting ſo. Strike up, and ſing the <hi>Chorus, Chor. Ah, what Charms have thoſe Eyes,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Pray hold, my Brothers coming.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>I am glad of it, ſince I cannot reclaim the Siſter from doting on Sobriety. I'le ſee what can be done on the Brother; go on.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Sings.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Then ſpight of my ſelf,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter Mr.</hi> Muchland <hi>above.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Ah, Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> you're upon the Ramble, I ſee; what time of Night is it?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>About two, and fair Weather; who would lye ſpending this pleaſant time in a lazy Bed, and then riſe to fry all day in the Sun?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, did not Nature intend the Night for Reſt, ſeem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to draw Curtains about us, and the Day for Action, diſplaying the great producer of it, Light.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>This Philoſophy may ſerve well enough for one not in Love, but 'faith my Body is too combuſtible to endure two fires at once; Love, and the Sun: and therefore I drink at Night to ſlacken than within, and ſleep in the Day to avoid that without.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſee you would ſeem a Philoſopher too, to juſtifie the drinking as caus'd by your Love, but my Siſter will ſcarce believe you in that.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:101839:6"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, Brother, but I will; for I do believe 'tis Love; Love of drinking, I mean, that cauſes the fire within he complains of, and ſo he drinks on to quench it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Gentlemen, the ſtreet may prove ſcandalous: <hi>Roſe,</hi> go, let 'em in.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Scandalous! if you mean to them, 'tis impoſſible; for they're as well known in the ſtreet as the Bell-man, and as duly expected by the Neighbour-hood to their Lodgings punctually to come home at break of day.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>You ſay right, Madam; the Smiths, Shoo-makers, Pew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terers, and Sadlers in our ſtreet have no meaſure to call up their Pren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices by, but the noiſe of my Fiddles playing me to my Lodging.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>He tells you true, Madam; for they heard once he was going to remove, and in great fright call'd a Veſtry the next Lord's Day, where it was propos'd to make a Collection amongſt them to pay for his Lodging, on Condition he would ſtay.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, faith, and a ſolemn preſent of ſaffron Cakes and Sack given to <hi>Townlove,</hi> to move me to it.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe <hi>below.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Gallants, you may enter; but Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> is not of my mind, to ſuffer it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Prethee why, <hi>Roſe;</hi> I know thou art not ſo cruel, but thou could'ſt find in thy heart ſometimes to let in a Friend later than this.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, it muſt be with greater expectation of a ſober de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meanour when they come in, then I could hope from you now.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Townlove, Roſe</hi> is a Perſon I much rely on, therefore prethee mannage the controverſie begun with her, whilſt I go and excuſe my ſelf to her Miſtreſs.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Ex. all but</hi> Roſe <hi>and</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir, Arguments are in vain to me, I'm ſo poſſeſt that Love and Wine are inconſiſtent together, that I think I could dy rather then recant my Opinion.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>And, <hi>Roſe,</hi> it may be in doing ſo, would'ſt be as ſolid a Martyr as many of thy Sex, who have, as they ſay, witneſſed with their Death, truths they no wayes underſtood, nor indeed lay half ſo obvious to their Reaſon.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:101839:6"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, will you pleaſe to come in; the noiſe that theſe Fiddles keep will allure more of you wandring Knights to enter, except the Door be ſhut.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>No, <hi>Roſe,</hi> thou and I will ſtand and guard the paſſage to this Inchanted Caſtle, where vil'd Matrimonical Love is purſu'd in theſe dayes of clearer light.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Why then, Sir, you dare not enter into any Houſe, it ſeems, that is defil'd with Honeſty; if thoſe be your principles, you and I are not proper Sentinels for one place, being Souldiers of two op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſite parties.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, <hi>Roſe,</hi> are you for no Love that is not bound by the ſpell of, To have and to hold, and the little Magick Circle of Gold, that Fools ſay, makes one of two Perſons as inconſiſtent, and diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent in their Natures, as the Stars that govern 'em; and as far aſun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der in their inclinations, as they are from one another in place.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Truly, Sir, I am altogether for being particular in Love, or for not being in Love at all, though I confeſs 'tis no great matter, I think, for any other tye than mutual conſent.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Divine <hi>Roſe!</hi> if thou art not now, or haſt not been particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar, as thou call'ſt it, already, then this free humour I'm afraid will make me thine in ſpight of all reſiſtance, and therefore dear <hi>Roſe,</hi> ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit of a Treaty, in order to a ſtricter League.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Which will begin on your part with a breach of Articles concerning ſome former commerce; that Amity is like to continue long, whoſe firſt Foundation is broken Faith.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>No doubts, <hi>Roſe,</hi> but muſt be explain'd on both ſides, to prevent future miſtakes, I muſt know whether I am the firſt diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verer of your Territories, that I may the better rate the curioſity, you ſhall know the true cauſe of my leaving my former Traffick, and ſeeking out new Countries.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, I am not ſo fond of the Alliance, as to ſpend time in the Treaty; and ſo farewell, if you will not come in.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Come in, ſayſt thou! I am ſo taken with thy humour, that I would follow thee, though it was to Church.</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
                  <pb n="8" facs="tcp:101839:7"/>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>The Scene changes into the Houſe, where is</hi> Merry, Much<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, <hi>his Siſter</hi> Honour, <hi>and the Fiddles.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, I'le go and dreſs my ſelf, and then Ramble with you.</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Do ſo; this Brother of yours, Madam, is a very honeſt Gentleman, and I have greater hopes of him then I have of you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Indeed, Sir, you have a great deal of Reaſon.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, good Madam, can you ſhew a juſt exception againſt my manner of Living?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, indeed, Sir, a thouſand, if it concern'd me, but I ſhall not need to take pains in particulars about a thing ſo remote.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, I muſt tell you, there is more thanks due to me for this Viſit, then you ſeem to beſtow by your cold indifferency.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Thanks for breaking my ſleep!</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>For breaking your ſleep, ſay you; marry, I hope to have your thanks for doing it before I dye, notwithſtanding your ſeeming ſober diſlikes of it now.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>For hope, 'tis an Eſtate entail'd upon Lovers and Fools. There is no diſpoſſeſſing them of it, and though I cannot certainly define by which of the Titles you hold, yet this for your comfort I can tell you, Fiddles, and crying Fire are much the ſame to me about two in the morning, and were I marry'd, I cannot certainly tell which I ſhould ſooner wiſh my Husband ſhould waken me with.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Madam, let your Servant wake you with Fiddles, and your Husband with Fire; the firſt provokes Dancing, the Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blem of Love, that never lets a man reſt, and the other is hot, and therefore requires a — Cooler.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Townlove,</hi> I thank thee for that—'tis the firſt time I e're heard thee ſpeak for ſitting up late; ſure thou haſt been drinking ſince I left thee without, thou art ſo thoughtful, nothing but Wine would have made thee arrived to the tenth part of this good Nature.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>No, truly, Sir, I have been loving, and loving a great deal for ſo little time.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:101839:7"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>The fire of thy Love is like that of Gun-powder, flaſh, noiſe, ſmoak, and Exit. Mine is kindled in heart of Oak, where 'tis laſting and uſeful.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>And which to preſerve the Block the longer, you quench every Night by drenching it in Liquor, and then with a great deal of puſſing and blowing you kindle it again by Noon.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>And is not that well, when you can have half the day to warm your ſelf by it? an't would but hold out at that rate I ſhould prove the beſt Husband in Town; but faith, Madam, take me be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I waſte too much, for this keeping the fire-light all Night will conſume fewel monſtrouſly.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>And 'tis two to one we ſhall ſit blowing our fingers half the long Winter of Marriage, for that's a cold time, I have heard many of you Gallants ſay.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, ſuch as <hi>Townlove</hi> here, that know no other way to heat themſelves but at the main fire. But we that practice the warm Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſe of Drinking, never go cold to Bed, and a warm Bed-fellows Arms is a pleaſant place I can tell you.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland <hi>dreſs'd.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Gentlemen, I am ready for your commands now, let's whither you pleaſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Why then, let's to your Miſtreſs, and ſerenade her, and call <hi>Ned Roſh</hi> her Brother up, and go to the <hi>Roſe</hi> Tavern for a Bottle of <hi>Burgundy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>With all my heart.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le bring you on your way, till you go embarque for drink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and then I'le take leave, being not willing to grow Sea-ſick to Night.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Brother <hi>Muchland,</hi> that muſt be, for ſo I know the Deſtinies have decreed; this <hi>Townlove</hi> is a very honeſt fellow, did he not de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light in lewd Company.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>One good turn is, the faults of my Company are not ſo viſible, nor do not make ſuch a noiſe as yours do.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>If thou underſtoodſt noiſe, thou would'ſt not ſay ſo, for is't not the whole noiſe of the Town; who's ſuch a ones Miſtreſs, what he allows her, and whether ſhe has any certainty ſettl'd on her, or muſt upon diſlike be caſt off, and according to the anſwers of theſe
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:101839:8"/>Queries ſhe is more or leſs reſpected, and makes the greater noiſe at her Lodgings in the Park, and at the Play Houſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>And good reaſon too; 'tis not the drinking of Wine, but your ability to pay for it makes you welcome to the drowſie Vintner at two in the Morning; and let the preciſe ſay what they will, 'tis plain they ne're complain of the ſins they themſelves get by, or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light in.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Sir, you are in the right, I ne're heard of a Vintner or Bawd that complained of Drinkers or Wenchers, except they broke Windows, or built Sconces, and I'le aſſure you I have known very devout People of both thoſe Employments.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>No doubt on't, People that would not have failed being at Church before the Pſalm was ſung for their Sundayes Dinner.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Truly it is the ſame in more warrantable Employments, for you ſhall never hear the Parſon ſpeak againſt the ſin his Patron is notoriouſly guilty of, or if he is forc't to Name it, it is in ſuch a whiſper, that few, except the Reader, can hear him.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Your Lawyer ne're ſpeaks againſt the forgery he is retain'd for; your Doctor, ne're againſt the cauſe of the Pox, nor will a Souldier be perſwaded there is any hurt in plundering.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Nor will all the Rhetorick a man has be enough to Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince a Tradeſman that he doth ill when he over-reaches them moſt that truſt him moſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Then ſince no Action, be it good or bad, but hath it's vouchers, I am for letting every one have his humour, and only beg that I may have mine, which terminates alwayes in the conſent of the parties I deal with, and the Devils in't if there can be harm in that, to which all Perſons concern'd give their approbation.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, thou'rt in the right, <hi>Townlove,</hi> and therefore let us by mutual conſent purſue our intentions.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>What, call up a Lady with a noiſe of Fiddles at two in the morning, for no other purpoſe but to break her ſleep; it ſhall never be ſaid <hi>Townlove</hi> was partaker in ſuch a Crime; therefore you that can Dance, ſhall; and you that cannot, ſhall try; for I will have my frolick.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>And good reaſon you have for it, Sir, for 'tis a ſhame that thoſe who are ſo us'd to Dance about the ſtreets all Night ſhould be
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:101839:8"/>able to do nothing tending to the ſame ſtirring faculty within Doors.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Then to your bus'neſs; firſt, the Catch in commendation of the Liberal Art of Wenching, and then a Dance, to ſhew the methodical motion of Reeling.</p>
                  <q>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                        <body>
                           <div type="song">
                              <head>Catch.</head>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> Boy, call the Coach; come, Jack, let's away:</l>
                              <l>'Tis tedious to ſit out this Tragical Play.</l>
                              <l>A Plague o'their pletting and dying in Rhime,</l>
                              <l>Let's drive to the Park</l>
                              <l>Before it be dark,</l>
                              <l>There we'l better diſpoſe of our Time.</l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> Stay, who is that ſo dreſt like a Queen?</l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> 'Tis the fine Lady Lofty, but let's not be ſeen:</l>
                              <l>For her Husband is ſurely gone out.</l>
                              <stage>Chor.</stage>
                              <l>— <hi>She ſearches to find</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>If a Friend will be kind,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>And treat her abroad with a Supper and 'bout.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="2">2. <hi>Why ſhould ſhe want that? Her Lords a brave Man.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="1">1. <hi>Ay,</hi> Jack, <hi>but they're marry'd.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="2">2. <hi>Then what two are you?</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="1">1. <hi>'Tis</hi> Will Lovewell <hi>and his pretty Miſs,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>He hath kept her this ſeven year, yet prethee,</hi> Jack, <hi>ſee</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>How jocund and merry they be,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>How Crown'd, and incircl'd with Bliſs.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <stage>Chor.</stage>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Love Revels, and Feaſts in hearts that are free,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>But languiſhing ſtarves if reſtrained he be.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="1">1. <hi>See, yonder ſits</hi> Well-born <hi>with his pretty Wife.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="2">2. <hi>They look as they'd ne're ſeen each other before.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="1">1. <hi>Shee ſeeks for her Gallant, and he o'my Liſe</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Hath a mind to be feaguing you Vizor-Mask-Whore.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>But ſtay, let me ſee; by Heav'ns 'tis ſo,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>That Mask hides a Lady I know,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Who ſeems for to dote on Husband and Honour,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>But look there,</hi> Ned Ranter <hi>has juſt fixt upon her.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <pb n="12" facs="tcp:101839:9"/>
                              <l n="2">2. <hi>She hath yielded, and ſee they do go.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="1">1. <hi>If Wives will do this,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Give me the true Miſs,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>She'd be hang'd e're ſhe'd ſerve a Man ſo.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <stage>Chor.</stage>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>They're Fools then that Marry, and ſtrive to conſine</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>In politick Chains what ſtill will be free;</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>No Fetters can hold a pow'r that's Divine,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Nor Shackles reſtrain great Loves Deity.</hi>
                              </l>
                           </div>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                  </q>
                  <stage>A Dance; and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eunt Dancing.</stage>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Manet</hi> Hon. <hi>and</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>What would I give, <hi>Roſe,</hi> to be a man but one Night, to ſee what pleaſure there is in the inſide of a Tavern; for ſure, it muſt be ſomething extraordinary maks Mre. <hi>Merry</hi> ſo continually delight in being there.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Madam, it is not hard to compaſs your wiſh.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>What, to be a man for a Night?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, to be a man as far as amounts to carry on the deſign of going to a Tavern; for I believe theſe honeſt good fellows never ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amine the inſide of every mans Breeches that keep 'em Company.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Roſe,</hi> you are a little too wanton.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, you are a little too preciſe; why, 'tis the bus'neſs of a Chamber-Maid to give hints of delight to her Lady when they are alone, and there is not one in ten, let them ſay what they will, but are pleas'd to hear ſomething to the purpoſe ſometimes.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Now out upon thee; I am afraid Mr. <hi>Townlove</hi> and you have had a conference lately, you are ſo apt to change my innocent diſcourſe of a Tavern to matters nearer his purpoſe, in which I'le aſſure you I am not at all curious.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Well then, Madam, let that alone, and as to your obſerving the delights of a Tavern, I can put you in a way immediately to do it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>What, without being known!</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, Madam; for the Suits, Perriwiggs, Hats, and Swotds that are to go to your younger Brothers into the Countrey, came home laſt Night, and your Brother has not ſeen them I am confident, if you and I put them on, we ſhall never be ſuſpected for any other then a couple of tight Bully Bocks.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>But ſhould we in this Habit intrude into their Company, I am afraid they'l make us drink, and I am not able to do that.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:101839:9"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>But I am, Madam, I'le warrant you as far as a Bottle or two, and you may put on Mr. <hi>Townlove</hi>'s humour, at which I'le Quarrel, and that ſhall be our Excuſe for leaving them before they agree to part.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, faith, I'le venture, for I long to ſatisfie my Curio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſity.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, let's make haſte to dreſs our ſelves.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
                  <stage>The end of the firſt Act.</stage>
               </sp>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="act">
               <head>The Second Act.</head>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland, Townlove, Merry, <hi>Fiddles, and Torches.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>STrike up, Boys, ſound Alarm to the ſleepy Sentinels of this Fortification.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Ah, what Charms have thoſe Eyes,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
                  <stage>They follow and make a noiſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Raſh <hi>above.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>What, ſober Mr. <hi>Muchland!</hi> I little ſuſpected to have ſeen you at the head of a Troop of Fiddles and Torches, ſcowring of the Streets, and beating up of Quarters at ſuch a time of Night.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>You ſee how pow'rful Example is, yet conſidering theſe honeſt Gentlemen, my Companions, I think this may be as becom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing an Exerciſe, as the following a pack of Doggs all day ſo hard, to kill my Horſes, and the Quarry only a rank Fox, for the noiſe of thoſe we Hunt, which now is much more Muſical.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, come, dreſs, dreſs, we are in great haſte, and have much bus'neſs to do before that great make-bate, the Sun, who lights your Lawyers, Uſurers, Scriveners, Merchants, and other formal fopps to go together by the Ears, do riſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I am afraid we have diſturb'd your Siſter with our noiſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:101839:10"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Prethee, dear <hi>Muchland</hi> no fears, for let her be diſturb'd as much as ſhe will, ſhe'l take it for a ſign of Love, to ſee that when her Servant is Rambling, he cannot chooſe but take her in his way, and let them never ſo much diſlike the man that doth it, there was never one of them yet that was diſpleas'd at being belov'd.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>I am of your mind, Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> they are the ſame in Lovers as they are in Footmen, ſo they have but enough to wear the Livery, they deſire but one to do the bus'neſs, and glory more in the Manies conſtant attendance, then they do in the ones ability for per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forming their How de's.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, <hi>Raſh,</hi> thou art i'th right; for till this way came up of keeping Miſſes, a Woman counted it a ſcandal to have but one Servant; 'tis true, they admitted them under the Name of Plato<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nicks, Friends, or Admirers, but would oblige them at the charge of their Lovers or Husbands, rather then loſe their Viſits; but ſince this impropriating of Womens Fleſh without Matrimony came in requeſt, 'tis counted a greater diſgrace amongſt themſelves to admit of two Gallants, then e're it was for a marry'd Woman to Cuckold her Husband. And Opinion being the ſole Governour of mens Actions; I believe this to be the only way to introduce Chaſtity into the Female Sex again, and to ſecure men in the knowledge of their own Children.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>I never knew you want an Argument to juſtifie Wenching in my Life. But come in, and I'le Dreſs me.</p>
                  <stage>Door opens.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Sound a Charge, and Enter.</p>
                  <stage>Ex. Singing and Playing.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>Scena Secunda. <hi>Scene a Tavern.</hi>
               </stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Ruffle, Tullam, <hi>and</hi> Breef, <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s from Play<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> with a Drawer;</hi> Ruffle <hi>with ſome Dice in his hand.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, ne're tell me o'that, Sir, you're <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> of Cheats, and I'le have my money again, or I'le ſo ſwinge you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Good Mr. <hi>Ruffle</hi> conſider this Gentleman as a meer Stran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger to me, and that money I have won of you, I have it fairly, and will keep it too in ſpight of your coun<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>rf<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>it Courage.</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Conſpiracy; a meer Conſpiracy, what t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> Devil, is not here a Dye hath nothing but fives upon it: here another with two ſixes, and there a third with two Quaters, and two <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>e's? I tell you 'tis a plain Conſpiracy, and I will have my money again.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:101839:10"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you know I am a meer Stranger to him, and met you at the Coffee-Houſe by chance, and truly, conſidering I have loſt all my money I might ju<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> ſuſpect.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Suſpect, ha, what would you ſuſpect? ha!</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Suſpect, Sir, look you, if you go to that, Sir, I might ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pect, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> that you drew me hither, and conſpir'd together to get my <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>, Sir, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap>eting thoſe Dice I ſee there, that I might ſuſpect, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Sirrah, thou Varlet, darſt thou talk thus to a Gentleman of my Quality, that can ſpend a thouſand pounds per <hi>annum,</hi> and be ne're the worſe, that ever I ſhould light into the Company of a Slave that ſpunges at Ordinaries upon the winning hands for his Bread: begs to go ſix pence upon 7, to 5, and being broke by paying Laun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreſs, or Lodging, ſets up again with a new borrow'd half-Crown.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Good <hi>Mr. Ruffle,</hi> be more civil; you know I brought you into the Houſe a Guinney, ſixteen ſhillings in ſilver, and a ſtuddle Watch-Caſe, and Chain, and have loſt them all; then me-thinks you might give me leave to ſpeak for my money.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Oh, Impudence! Drawer, what's to pay?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>Three pounds, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Lok you there, Raſcal! is't likely you ſhould be ſet by us to get the value you ſpeak of; when the Reckoning comes to more. Thou Dogg, I have loſt fifty Guinneys, beſides three pounds in ſilver; and you come in with your ſtuddle Watch-Caſe and Chain, and we should deſign upon you in the Devil's name; very likely.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I have more money ſomewhere, and I believe all this heat is becauſe I had no more about me to loſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Damn'd Raſcal, doſt provoke me? I'le kick thee up the Chimney.</p>
                  <stage>Kicks him.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Lord, Sir, pray, Sir, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>, what de'e mean, Sir? we ſhall talk about this anon.</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Hold, <hi>Mr. Ruffle,</hi> this is not fair, nor muſt be here; we will have no Quatrelling, if I can help it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I vow to Gad, Mr. <hi>Fullam,</hi> you are a civil Gentleman, but there is no enduring of this Rogue; therefore, prethee give me leave to kick him out of the Company.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir, that need not, Sir; on Condition you'l threw
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:101839:11"/>thoſe Dice out of the Window, I'le borrow five Guinneys of the Drawer, and loſe them too, if it be my ill Fortune; but I'le aſſure you I'le look to the Dice we play with.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Well then; Drawer, go to your maſter, and bid him ſend me twenty Guinneys.</p>
                  <stage>Throws away the Dice.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſhall, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>And do you hear? bring me five.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>It ſhall be done, Sir.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Ex. Drawer and</hi> Fullam.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>I proteſt, Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> I am ſorry I have offended you; for you know 'tis not my cuſtome to Quarrel at the Ordinary, or any where elſe, but loſe my money as quietly as men of better Eſtates do.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Then this <hi>Fullam</hi> is a Rogue; but 'ſore Heaven, if I take him at his tricks, I'le cut's Ears off, or have my money again.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>You have reaſon; but Gad, I have ſome Tools here about me, as good Lows and Highs as e're ran on ſmooth Table; Gad, you might, and you would ſerve him a trick for his trick.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>And will, by Heaven; lend me them then.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>There, Sir, theſe are Lows, and theſe are High runners; you'l never find more than threes run on theſe, nor leſs than fours on theſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Then we'l to paſſage.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Sir, let's into our Room, and ſeem angry ſtill.</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>What advantage have men of Courage over Cowards; how tame this Rogue is with his beating? I have got ſome Reputa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion for my money in huffing this Rogue.</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>Scene changes to a Hall.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Merry, Muchland, Betty, Raſh, <hi>and Maid in Night Dreſs.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, you ſee the Excellencies of theſe Fellows: Was not the Sport you have had worth waking for?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, truly, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Madam, I never do worſe than this; my Bottle,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:101839:11"/>Fiddle, and Friend, are the Delights of my Life, and had not <hi>Cupid</hi> watch't a time when I was ſober, and ſhot me as I ſtood muſing on this Gentleman's Siſter, I think I ſhould never have thought of other pleaſures; but now ſpend at leaſt two hours in the twenty four, in muſing, ſighing, hoping, wiſhing, and fearing.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>A grievous affliction I'le aſſure you, Sir; and if I were able to perſwade the Lady that has this intereſt in your heart two hours of the day, ſhe ſhould e'en releaſe her part for altogether; for I think the twelfth part of a Man's heart is no more worth keeping then the twelfth part of a ſhilling, a ſum too little to be beſtow'd on the meaneſt Beggar.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, Madam, you ſpeak of a heart that can be divided; but alas, 'tis not ſo in mine; ſhe has right of common in the whole, every part is as much hers as any part, and ſhe can incloſe it when ſhe pleaſes, being Lady of the Mannor.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>But I am afraid you'd ſoon break down the Fences, and plead a preſcription of Liberty, eſpecially to that part that lyes near<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt the Water-courſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>What, a Lover! and in the preſence of his Miſtreſs, yet plead for the Adverſe party! O, <hi>Monſtrum Horrendum!</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, Sir, a whole Lover may have Liberty to ſpeak againſt the twelfth part of one, there is no proportion between e'm.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, 'tis poſſible the twelfth part of one heart may be more then the whole of another.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Brother <hi>Mushland,</hi> I think there you are met with.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſhould be loath to think the Lady meant a compariſon between your heart and mine; but if ſhe did, I would be glad ſhe would take the trouble of ſurveying both before ſhe gave final Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in ſo difficult a cauſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Since I pretend a Title to neither, nor know any body that doth, you ſhall pardon me if I concern not my ſelf about the Buts, Bounds, Quantity, or Quality of the premiſes.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, you that command ſo many hearts, you think to deſcend to the obſervation of particulars is below you; but ſince you will at laſt find it convenient to Build, you ought to ſurvey well the place you intend to ſit down upon.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you ſay well; and when I begin to think of that, I ſhall
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:101839:12"/>not fail to be very circumſpect in my Choice.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>But do it quickly, Madam, Life's ſhort, and if you in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to enjoy the fruit your ſelf, you muſt plant betimes.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Raſh <hi>and</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, this Brother of yours is more circumſpect in dreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing himſelf for the Tavern, then Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> was to come to his Miſtreſs.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>It is a ſign he has a greater reſpect for the one, then Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> has for the other.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay rather, Madam, impute it to the exceſs of my deſires, which prompted me to ſuch haſte, as I regarded nothing but the hopes of ſeeing you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, let's away to the <hi>Roſe,</hi> for 'tis almoſt Day; and 'tis more ſcandalous to enter a Tavern, then come out of one in a Morning.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis true, had not we the laudable excuſe of Fiddles and Link-Boys, which are infallible ſigns of no early Riſers.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, all the Good Fellows we meet in the Street, and all that are in the Tavern are part of our Company, know e'm, or know e'm not.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Provided, they carry good Teſtimony that they riſe not thus early about bus'neſs, for if we meet any ſuch, they or we muſt change ſides of the way.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Ne're fear it, Gentlemen, ſuch, if they meet you, will give you the way without Quarrelling; for if you look on e'm as Fools, they think as ſure that you are Mad-men.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>And with very good reaſon; and therefore, deſiring I may be ſuſpected for one of theſe fooliſh Men of bus'neſs, I beg Liberty to give way to you Men of the Moon-light.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Be but a Mad-man to the Tavern, <hi>Townlove,</hi> and then go away like a Fool if thou wilt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, come on then; I will endure worſe denominations then theſe, ſo I may but have my humour.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Rogues, Raſcals; come away, and ſound a retreat to Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> who ſcarce marches off with flying Colours as I did from my Miſtreſs.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I dare ſay he is no more without nopes then you are
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:101839:12"/>without Confidence.</p>
                  <stage>Enter Fiddles and Torches.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Madam, in ſpight of Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> I will not believe my ſelf ſo miſerable, as to be paſt all hopes.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> nor need not, if it be'nt your own fault.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Fie, Brother.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Fie, Siſter; I'le tell thee, <hi>Muchland,</hi> ſhe's more afraid of being forſaken, then you are of being ſlighted.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I dare not think my ſelf ſo happy.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>You are a Fool then, let her deny what I ſaid, if ſhe can.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Brother, this is unſufferable.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, come, prethee come away, there is ſuch fooling and diſſembling with theſe Women.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt all but</hi> Betty <hi>and Maid, with Fiddles playing before e'm.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet,</speaker>
                  <p>This Brother of mine has ſo throughly vex'd me, by diſcovering my inclination, that I ſhall not be able to ſleep for thoughts of it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Maid.</speaker>
                  <p>Why ſhould you be troubl'd, Madam, ſince me-thinks 'tis well he knows it, 'twill put an end to the bus'neſs quickly.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>But if he ſhould ſlight me, I believe I ſhould dye.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Maid.</speaker>
                  <p>Ne're fear that, Madam, you have him too faſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, I will to bed; no more this Morning.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>The Street Scene.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Entes at one Door,</hi> Muchland, Townlove, Merry, <hi>and</hi> Raſh: <hi>At the other,</hi> Honour <hi>and</hi> Roſe <hi>in Men's Cloaths.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Stand, who goes there?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Ah, Roſe, 'tis they!</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>No matter; what are you that queſtion who we are in ſuch high Terms?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Are you men of buſineſs? For if you be, you muſt leave this ſide of the Street clear to us.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Gentlemen, do you think we look like perſons that are ſent
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:101839:13"/>to fetch Doctors, Apothecaries, or Midwives thus early; or, that we riſe this Morning not to fail meeting at ſome zealous brothers, for the Spiritual comforts of a morning Lecture; no faith, we are men of no more bus'neſs then your ſelves.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Are you Good Fellows, or Wenchers, that you are upon the Ramble ſo late?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Partly t'one, partly to'ther, like moſt of Mankind; but by what Authority do you examine us thus?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>We have a Commiſſion to take up all ſtragglers we meet, and carry them to the <hi>Roſe</hi> Tavern.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Where, after Drinking all Night, you intend to take your Mornings Draughts; is't not ſo?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis true, that's the ſcope of our Commiſſion.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>We are for you then, though my friend here never Drinks; he's for pleaſures of another Nature.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I have Commiſſion to Diſpence him as well as my ſelf, he being I find of our Brigade.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Fall into your places then.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>But not ſo eaſily I believe, you will think we did not deſign to play the Philoſophers: No, we are for mirth and madneſs, fro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licks of ſome noiſe muſt tempt us to engage in your Company, elſe we are going to thoſe that know truly how to be merry; men of met<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle, that though they will not break Laws, have an Art of ſtretching of e'm as far as the beſt pleading Caſe Lawyer that wears a Coif —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>And that is further by half then any Shoo-maker can his Leather; for they can fit Law to every Laſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Therefore in plain terms, Gentlemen, we muſt ſee ſome frolick perform'd that will convince we are not like to loſe precious time in your Company, or we ſhall take you for ſome Conſtables, Church-wardens, Sides-men, and Over-ſeers in Diſguiſe, a going to Ferret, and ſet Toils for the tame Game of <hi>Whetſtone</hi>'s Park.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Your ſcruples of Conſcience are ſo weighty, there ought to be much care taken to ſolve the doubts.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Your Company ſeems ſo good, that let the Conditions be but poſſible on which we are to gain your acquaintance they ſhall be perform'd: What ſay we, ſhall we break Windows, pull down Signs, beat Conſtables, or fire the Church —</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:101839:13"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Hold! Fire <hi>Coven-Garden</hi> Church; Heav'n forbid! If that ſhou'd once be done, then ſhou'd I be condemn'd never to hear Common-Prayer again.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>And what a loſs would that be to the Church, to have ſuch a Pillar remov'd?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Coven-Garden</hi> Church! It is the Theatre of Beauty, and Rendevouz of Miſſes and Gallants. I dare avow 'tis a greater Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage to Love's Empire then both the Play-houſes are. No, I'le have no firing of <hi>Coven-Garden</hi> Church in my Company; any other Church in the Kingdome I think may be ſpar'd.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Gentlemen, theſe ſort of frolicks we are not for; there's no venturing upon ſuch without the ſecurity of as many Lives as a Cat; beſides, we hate to be giving the lye to Reverend Men of the long Robe, in crying not guilty, my Lord.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Invent, invent then! What is't we muſt do?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Can you Dance all of you? The place is convenient here within the Piazza.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>We can do ſomething like it, moſt of us.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I wiſh we had but a Bell then; we would wake all the People of the Piazza, and ſhew e'm by our mirth, the difference between Living as we do, and dying; that is, Eating, Drinking, Sleeping, and Melancholy moving to no purpoſe, as they do.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>We ſhall but loſe time in looking for a Bell-man, and I have a Trumpet here will make a greater noiſe; I carry it alwayes with me, to ſound at ſome particular Healths.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>That will do much better, the rarity of it will beget more attention.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come then, a Levite; my Man here has a Speech to go round with: I uſe it at my Friends Windows as I Ramble to my Lodgings a Mornings.</p>
                  <stage>A Levite ſounded.</stage>
                  <p>Come, I'le ſpeak it firſt at this Corner my ſelf, and then he ſhall about with it, whilſt we fall to our Dance.</p>
                  <q>
                     <l>GRave ſober Sots riſe from your Beds,</l>
                     <l>And juſt thruſt out your Logger-heads,</l>
                     <l>With Eyes half ſhut, and ſenſes dull'd</l>
                     <l>You'l ſee a little how you're gull'd,</l>
                     <pb n="22" facs="tcp:101839:14"/>
                     <l>And kept from pleaſures of the Dark,</l>
                     <l>By precepts wiſe of Lamb and Lark.</l>
                     <l>But learn by us your Lives to mend,</l>
                     <l>For Life is ſhort, and time will end:</l>
                     <l>And when you're dead, for what you do,</l>
                     <l>Your merry Heirs will laugh at you.</l>
                  </q>
                  <p>Morrow Mr. <hi>Scrape,</hi> Morrow Mrs. <hi>Scrape,</hi> Morrow Mr. <hi>Save-all,</hi> Morrow my Lord <hi>Sober,</hi> Morrow my Lady Penſive, Morrow Mr. <hi>Catch-good:</hi> Morrow, you Sleepers all, good Morrow.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter Servant.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                  <p>Stand upon your Guard, Gentlemen, the Conſtable and Watch are coming.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Let e'm come, I have a ſure way to keep ſuch Dogs from Barking, as can be; if our party be two ſtrong, they flye off courſe; but if not, I take him by the hand, and cry good Mr. Conſtable don't you know me? Strait with the help of their horns they peep in my face, whilſt he has time to conſider that he is richer by half a Crown then he was; then, as in an extaſie of Joy, he crys, ha, Sir, is it you? Will you have any of my Watch wait on you? Which I de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nying, we part with as many farewells, and good wiſhes to one ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, as if we had tumbl'd together in one Belly, though it may be we ne're ſaw one anothers faces before.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter Conſtable and Watch.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>Stand, who goes there?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>No body.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>What, are all you no body?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſay, no body goeth here, for we are all ſtanding.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>You are merry Gentlemen, but I ſhall alter your humour preſently; come before the Conſtable one of you, keep the Peace in the Kings Name, keep the Peace, I am his Majeſties Conſtable. Oh, I ſhall be kill'd, I am a dead Man: Oh, my Wife and Children: I'le have you all hang'd if I be kill'd: I ſay, keep the Peace; in the King's Name, keep the Peace.</p>
                  <stage>They all advance with their ſwords drawn, and away run the Watch.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>What, Mr. <hi>Laſt,</hi> is't you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, an't pleaſe your Worſhip, your Worſhips own Shoo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maker;
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:101839:14"/>good Sir, don't uſe me ill, your Worſhips ſhooes are ready for you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Uſe thee ill! What, my man of mid-night! Do'ſt think we'l uſe thee ill? How does thy Wife and Daughter <hi>Joan?</hi> they are pretty Rogues both.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, Mr. <hi>Townlove,</hi> you are pleas'd to ſay ſo, but 'tis your goodneſs more then their deſert truly; though indeed they alwayes talk of your Worſhip, and are near falling out ſometimes about you, in arguing which loves you beſt, but I to keep the Peace part them, and take my Daughters part, becauſe poor thing! My Wife is her Mother in Law, I hope your Worſhip will not be angry at it —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>No, no, Mr. Conſtable, by any means keep the Kings Peace within doors, it will keep it ſelf without.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Mr. <hi>Laſt,</hi> how many Priſoners have you that are not able to pay Ranſom? I am reſolved to Act the Juſtice, and ſet all at Liberty after due Examination.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>Why truly, Sir, we have only took four Gentlewomen, which we were carrying to the Round-houſe; I'le make the Watch bring e'm before your Worſhip — Bring the Priſoners.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter Watch with four Priſoners.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Madam, turn up your head, and let's ſee your face very well! What is your employment?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Prethee <hi>Merry,</hi> be not impertiennt, what ſhould a pretty Womans employment be? Let me ſpeak to her; Come, Madam! fear nothing if you tell Truth: Are you a Park, Play-Houſe, or Street-plyer? Do you Live upon Induſtry, or are you kept?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>1. <hi>Wom.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>I am kept, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>What makes you out at this time of Night?</p>
                  <p>This may be my own caſe.</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>1. <hi>Wom.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>I am kept by one that allows me but forty ſhillings a week, and makes at leaſt ten Guinneys of me; for he bargain'd I ſhould admit any Friend of his, and he brings almoſt every day a new one, and ſometimes two or three, with whom he keeps ſo good Intelligence, that whatſoever they give me, I can never ſink a ſingle ſhilling for Coach-hire; he ſometimes lets me out too, as it hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen'd this Night, to a Country Parſon, whoſe Land-lady ſuſpecting the matter, and Jealous of loſing any thing her ſelf, turn'd me out
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:101839:15"/>of doors without a penny of Money, ſo I fell into the Watches hands, and I hope, ſince you ſeem a civil Gentleman, you will re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deem me, for it will be very injurious to my Honour to go to the Round-houſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Thy Honour ſhall be as ſafe as a Thief in a Mill, ne're fear it; Come, Madam! Your Quality.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>2. <hi>Whore.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>My buſineſs lyeth altogether in the City, Sir; for I find them the beſt Cuſtomers.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>But how ſtruck you into that Trade?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>2. <hi>Who.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Truly, by meer chance, Sir; for ſitting one day in Maſque at the Play-houſe, in the middle Gallery, ſome Clerks began to talk wildly to me, till an Ancient, Grave Man, who proved ſince to be a Packer to Merchants, rebuk'd them, and ſaid, their Diſcourſe was ſinful; then giving me a tread on the Toe, and a pinch on my Arm, went out; I follow'd him, hoping he'd prove lucky, and ſo he did, for beſides his own bounty, he hath brought me acquainted with ſo many Rich Citizens, that I have more work then I can turn to, though I confeſs they being moſt Old, I have diſpatch'd half a ſcore ſometimes in a day.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>But after your abundance of Trading at that, how came you to this end of the Town?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>2. <hi>Who.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Truly, Sir, I Love a Young Gentleman that I keep, whom I came to ſee, and having given him all the money I had, I was going back to turn the penny.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>A very honeſt, induſtrious Woman this, ſhe ſhall have no harm: Come, let's ſee, what's your buſineſs?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>3. <hi>Who.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>You ſha'not ſee my Face, I'le go to Priſon ſooner:</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, ay, ſhe's a ſtubborn Jade, and call'd me Cuckold.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>3. <hi>Who.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>And ſo you are one, to uſe poor Women thus: Mr. <hi>Town-love,</hi> let me ſpeak with you — 'Tis I —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Truly, Mr. <hi>Laſt,</hi> I think ſhe ſpeaks to the purpoſe in cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling of you Cuckold, for this uſage ſhe ſhall not ſhew her Face. <hi>Will Merry,</hi> 'tis his Wife.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>The Devil 'tis; 'twas lucky then we met, or how would ſhe have got off.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>She'd have ſaid it was to watch his haunts ſhe came abroad, or ſome ſuch thing — ſhe would have tam'd him quickly, for 'tis
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:101839:15"/>a very Devil of her Tongue, and Cuckolds him almoſt before his Face.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, who are you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>4. <hi>Wom.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>A very good Gentlewoman both born and bred; I am a Presbyterian Miniſters Daughter.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>A ſubſtantial Title to Gentility, who will ſay after this the Crown is the Fountain of Honour, when they that pull'd it down can make Gentlewomen.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis poſſible her own Employment doth mote entitle her to it, therefore let's know that.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>4. <hi>Wom.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I have had a great mind to be a Player, and have offer'd my ſelf to both Houſes, and truly moſt of the ſharers have had me ſeverally at their Chambers to try me, and they all ſay, I do very well; but 'tis the Envy of the Women already there, that fearing I ſhould out-do e'm, keep me out, as I was told by two or three of the hired men of the Duke's Houſe, with whom I have been to Night, and ſpent all my money, but I do not doubt to find Friends to bring it about, for there are two or three Perſons of Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity have undertaken it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay, then there's no fear of ſucceeding.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>4. <hi>Wom.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>No, I hope not; alas, I deſire little or nothing for my pains, I would only ſhew my ſelf on the Stage, and then, perhaps, I may get a good Husband, or at leaſt, ſome Fool that will keep me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Honeſt good Women all; and are not you hard-hearted to diſturb the Lawful endeavours of ſuch well-minded People, Mr. Conſtable — Well, there are Reſolutions taken by ſome Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of my Acquaintance to make you keep cloſer to your Lawful buſineſs — which is indeed to cry Fire, prevent Houſe-breaking, and ſnore on Stalls according to your primitive inſtitution, and not to ſet to Ranſom, or Impriſon People induſtriouſly improving the two great works of Whoring and Drinking. War is declar'd, and ſhall be carry'd on againſt all the Obſtructions of Trade, as you ſhall hear in a Song lately publiſh'd, in which all muſt bear their parts.</p>
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:101839:16"/>
                  <q>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                        <body>
                           <div type="song">
                              <head>Song.</head>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> THe Trade of wine is much decay'd of late;</l>
                              <l>The Vintners complain, and the Cuſtoms abate,</l>
                              <l>For Pickaroon Bill-man in every Street,</l>
                              <l>Like Capers make prize of all Traders they meet.</l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> Come then, 'tis time to ſcowr alongſt the Coaſt;</l>
                              <l>To re-take good Fellows, who elſe may be loſt:</l>
                              <l>'I is Lawful thoſe Foes to invade,</l>
                              <l>Who rob us of Honour, and hinder our Trade;</l>
                              <l>And a damn'd Zealous Conſtable 'midſt of his Watch-men</l>
                              <l>Does Trading more harm, then a Squadron of Dutch-men;</l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> Weigh Anchor then, and hoiſt up Sail;</l>
                              <l>Nore and by Weſt it blows a merry Gale.</l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> The Glaſs is run, ho, ſtar-board, Watch, turn out;</l>
                              <l>Heark, did you hear, that Gun was from a Scout.</l>
                              <l>Run to the top,</l>
                              <l n="3">
                                 <hi>3.</hi> Hey Boys, I ſee a Fleet,</l>
                              <l>They bear hard up to us; we quickly ſhall meet.</l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> All hands to prayers, and make ready to fight,</l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> You need not, their Flags are all white;</l>
                              <l>That Colour denotes them for Wine or a Wench;</l>
                              <l>All Half-ſhirts are for us, as ſure as the <hi>French.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>They hale our Scouts, me-thinks I hear e'm call,</l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> Whence your Fleet?</l>
                              <l n="3">
                                 <hi>3.</hi> From <hi>White-Hall.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> VVhence your Fleet?</l>
                              <l n="3">
                                 <hi>3.</hi> From <hi>White-hall.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> VVe are Friends to e'm, then cry, Huzza.</l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> Once again, Huzza.</l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> And again, Huzza.</l>
                              <l n="3">
                                 <hi>3.</hi> They are Friends to us, then cry, Huzza.</l>
                              <l n="3">
                                 <hi>3.</hi> Once again, Huzza.</l>
                              <l n="3">
                                 <hi>3.</hi> Once again, Huzza.</l>
                              <l n="4">
                                 <hi>4.</hi> And again, Huzza, huzza, huzza.</l>
                              <pb n="27" facs="tcp:101839:16"/>
                              <l>Now we are all met, let's draw into a Line;</l>
                              <l>Charge every man his Glaſs of VVine,</l>
                              <l>'Tis our Royal high Admirals Health,</l>
                              <l>VVhilſt we drink all Night,</l>
                              <l>He does Hero-like Fight,</l>
                              <l>To reſcue the Kingdoms Honour and VVealth.</l>
                              <l>Let Trumpets ſound, and all at once give Fire,</l>
                              <l>If the Enemy comes, we'l ſoon make e'm Retire.</l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> Let's Charge them again, for a Health to the King.</l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> They come, they come, their Bell-man does Ring.</l>
                              <l n="3">
                                 <hi>3.</hi> Their Caps, Staves, and Lanthorns I ſpie,</l>
                              <l>They've horns in their Flags, and they bear e'm on high.</l>
                              <l n="4">
                                 <hi>4.</hi> Fall on then, fall on, tan tara rara, &amp;c.</l>
                              <l n="1">
                                 <hi>1.</hi> They flye, they flye.</l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> Then give a Broad-ſide, and cry, <hi>Vive le Roy, Vive le Roy.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l n="2">
                                 <hi>2.</hi> Give the Broad-ſide, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                              </l>
                           </div>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                  </q>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Now theſe four Gentlewomen will make our Dance the better.</p>
                  <stage>Dance.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, to every Lady a Link and a Watch-man for ſafe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guard to their Lodgings.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>3. <hi>VVom.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Except me, Sir, mine is not far off.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis true, you ſhall only have one of my Links; Mr. Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable, no more Pris'ners to Night, as you tender my good Grace; and there's a Crown to Drink.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Conſt.</speaker>
                  <p>VVe'l know no other Juſtice hereafter but your, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Now every one to their ſeveral abidings, and we for the <hi>Roſe,</hi> ſound a Charge, and let's aſſault the place.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt omues.</stage>
               </sp>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="act">
               <pb n="28" facs="tcp:101839:17"/>
               <head>The Third Act.</head>
               <stage>The Scene a Tavern.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Ruffle, Breef, Fullam, <hi>and Drawer.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>COme, come, Sir, theſe are no Jeſting matters, I'le not be cheated of all my Money thus.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>How do you mean cheated, Mr. <hi>Ruffle?</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>How do I mean? Did I not find a Dye with all Sinks, and others of the like Nature?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>I love you for that, I'faith, Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> I hope you don't take me for a Cully.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Nor ſhall you make me one, if I can help it, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, ſay, was there not ſuch Dice here? we'l find afterwards who brought e'm in.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſaw no ſuch Dice, not I.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Nor I, I'le aſſure you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Hey day, here's fine Rogues; Drawer, did not you ſee the Dice I ſpeak of?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir, not I; 'tis true, I heard you ſay ſome ſuch thing, but I could not believe Gentlemen would put falſe Dice upon one another.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>No, but Cheats will.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>How do you mean, Sir, I ſay? Cheat again! war the third time, Mr. <hi>Ruffle.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſay, this Gentleman and I are Cheated, and by you, that's plain, and if he'le be rul'd by me, you ſhan'not carry it off ſo.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>d <hi>Ful.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>I can endure no longer: Come, come, come, draw, raw, Sir, for I will have ſatisfaction for this abuſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le bear no witneſs.</p>
                  <stage>Exit Draw.</stage>
               </sp>
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:101839:17"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <l>Are you for that ſport?</l>
                  <l>We'le ſwinge you:</l>
                  <l>Do you think to carry it off ſo?</l>
                  <l>This is brave i'faith.</l>
                  <l>Firſt, Cheated, and then Hector'd;</l>
                  <l>Suffer this, and ſuffer all.</l>
                  <stage>All this while be baſt'es about, throws his Hat away, pulls off his Perriwig, and ſeems to be preparing to fight.</stage>
                  <p>Come, Sir, why don't you prepare? Do you ſee how he braves us?</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>To</hi> Breef.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>What do you mean, Sir?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Wee'l beat him, take out money again, and then have him toſt in a Blanket.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſhall not ſtain my Honour in being two againſt one.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I am croſs bit I ſee.</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <p>Nay, I can as well ſpare what I loſt, as you can yours, and it ſhall ne're be ſaid, I fought to recover anothers money, that would do no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing for it himſelf; give me your hand, Mr. <hi>Fullam,</hi> I am very glad 'twas your Fortune to get it, ſince it is mine to loſe it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Full.</speaker>
                  <p>This is but trivial ſatisfaction, Sir, for the abuſes you have put upon me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Hang't, Man, Paſſion, meer Paſſion; give loſers leave to ſpeak, I wou'd take twice as much for half the money, and I think I value my Honour as much as another (if I can but get off with Credit now.)</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, I think you ſpeak Reaſon, therefore, pay the Reckoning, and we are Friends.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>How do you mean, Mr. <hi>Fullam?</hi> Have not you got all the money?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>And will keep it, Sir; therefore reſolve to pay the Reckon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Plague on't, I ne're value three or four pounds; and it may be thou haſt particular occaſion for this ſum of money at preſent, then we'l ne're ſtand upon ſmall matters, I'le do't. But for you, Sir, I'le talk with you for your Highs and Lows.</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Very pretty, i'faith, a well fram'd Dialogue: Good Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> 'tis too plain; do you think your counterfeit Quatrels ſhall carry it off ſo? I ſhall ſtand by, and ſee my ſelf cheated of my me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, and take it kindly I have loſt it, becauſe you can Rally one ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:101839:18"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>What do you mean by this, Sir?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you are a ſtranger to me, and I can't blame you for what you have done; but to be ſet and bubled by Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> on pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of Friendſhip, is unſufferable.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>What the Devil, is not one kicking enough for you in one Night? Muſt I be bound to wear out my ſhooes upon you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, come, Sir, I know when to take a kicking, and when not. I bore with it then, in hopes you would have ſo manna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged the Dice I lent you, as to have won money for me, but on the contrary, you plac'd e'm upon our ſelves: therefore, Sir, refund, refund, I'le not loſe a groat of the money I loſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>But ſure you don't hope to carry it off ſo: Have I any of your money?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>But your Friend hath for your uſe, and I'le look no further then your ſelf for it; therefore, my money, or Draw.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>'Fore Heav'n this is pretty; then it ſeems you both deſign'd upon me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Sir, will you repay me?</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter Drawer.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> here is a great many Gentlemen with Fiddles, hearing you were here, are reſov'd to come up to you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>What ſhall I do? Gentlemen, ſtep into another Room, I'le come and give you full ſatisfaction preſently.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, I am content to wait a little.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Ex. all but</hi> Ruff.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>The Devils in my luck, I never get a little Reputation by beating a Man, but preſently ſome body or other huffs me out of it again, and then all my Honour flyes in Fumo. 'Tis true, I am a Coward, but no body need e're a known it but my ſelf, if I had not a fooliſh deſire to be thought valiant, and ſo muſt ſtill be picking Quarrels with all I think like my ſelf. And I gad, 'tis not once in twenty times, but I miſs my Man and get a beating.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Merry, Townlove, Raſh, Muchland, Honour, Roſe, <hi>and Fiddles.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>What, <hi>Ruffle</hi> alone in a Tavern at four in a Morning, that's a thing I ne're was guilty of.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, come, Table and Chairs.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, <hi>Will Merry,</hi> to tell thee the truth, I have been
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:101839:18"/>bubling a couple of Culleys to Night, and the poor things having loſt all their money are ſtaying for more in another Room.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, that doth not uſe to be thy way, for I have known thee oſtner a Bublee then a Bubler.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>That's true, but when I grant out my Letters of Mart to my Highs and Lows, there's no Man ſooner takes in repriſal then I; and I'faith, they have been all at work to Night.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>What have you won?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Let me ſee; fifty Guinneys, three pounds in ſilver, and twenty Guinneys more they borrowed of the Maſter of the Houſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>And did they not ſmoak you, as their term is?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, a little; but one of e'm beginning to prate, I kickt him ſoundly.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Thou Boy; now I believe nothing of the whole matter: Thou venture to kick a Man, 'tis impoſſible.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, this 'tis, becauſe I am a little compliſant ſometimes, and put up injuries from Gentlemen, therefore, you, it ſeems, have mean thoughts of me, but you ſhall hear; come hither, <hi>Stephen.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>Your pleaſure, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Did not you ſee me kick a Gentleman ſoundly to Night for talking to me of Cheating?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, Sir, I'le aſſure you, I was afraid you would hurt him.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>And was not there twenty Guinneys borrowed of your Maſter?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Draw.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, Sir; and five of me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>That's true (go thy ways) law you now, I had forgot that five Guinneys.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Miracles, Miracles, Miracles, give us Wine there; Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racles are not ceaſt: Here's a Health to <hi>Ruffle</hi>'s Converſion, <hi>Town<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>love;</hi> thou ſhalt pledge this, if thou never drink'ſt more.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>All this while</hi> Ruffle <hi>ſtruts about.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Sir, you muſt pardon me, if I don't know ſome great cauſe for it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Thy Ear.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Gentlemen, you know he is a merry Man every way, let him have his frolick: La, la, la, la, la, Sir, my Service to you, <hi>Will Merry</hi>'s Health.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="32" facs="tcp:101839:19"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I drink no Wine.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Damme, not pledge me, Sir, 'fore Heav'n but you muſt, or I ſhall throw it in your face.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Good Sir, be not rude, the Gentleman has our word to excuſe him.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>If he hath your word, let him paſs it. la, la, la, la.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I commend it to you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>I never drink by Commendations, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Well done, Boy; here's another milk-ſop: What, can't he drink neither?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, Sir, or any thing elſe with you that you dare.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>'Fore Heav'n a Lad of mettle; give me thy hand: Here's a health to all that dare, and a fig for men that dare not do any thing.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I'le pledge it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Some Wine, there; give every one of the Muſick a glaſs in his hand</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> I congratulate the change, and if I have any intereſt in my Lady <hi>Turnup,</hi> ſhe ſhall be yours, ſince the onely ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtacle is remov'd.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Mr. <hi>Townlove,</hi> you ſee men will ſhew themſelves ſuch one time or other. 'Las, the ſtouteſt Bully Rock of e'm all ne're went to ſingle Rapier in ſwadling Cloaths, they had all a time to begin: La, la, la, la.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>You are i'th' right, Mr. <hi>Ruffle;</hi> come, the Catch.</p>
                  <q>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                        <body>
                           <div type="song">
                              <head>Song.</head>
                              <lg>
                                 <l n="1">
                                    <hi>1.</hi> BOy, bring a Glaſs without marks, to confine</l>
                                 <l>The Ebbs and the Floods of our Drinking;</l>
                                 <l>Our Cups ſhall be heap'd with a full-tide of Wine,</l>
                                 <l>Till our Tongues do ſpeak wit without thinking.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <l n="2">
                                    <hi>2.</hi> We will with Wines, Aetherial fire,</l>
                                 <l>Like ſubtile Chymiſts, Bodies change;</l>
                                 <l>That without words each mans deſire</l>
                                 <l>Shall through the others fancy range.</l>
                                 <pb n="33" facs="tcp:101839:19"/>
                                 <l n="1">
                                    <hi>1.</hi> Wine ſhall waſh off our Earthly parts,</l>
                                 <l>And to new Creatures mold us;</l>
                                 <l n="2">
                                    <hi>2.</hi> We'l take off our Bouls,</l>
                                 <l>Till we mingle our Souls,</l>
                                 <l>And the World grows too little to hold us.</l>
                                 <stage>Chor.</stage>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>We'l, &amp;c.</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l n="1">1. <hi>All hands to work then, time ſlides away,</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>Night chides our ſloath, and haſtens on the day;</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l n="2">2. <hi>Then the Sun will bring heat</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>For our Limbeck ſo high,</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>And make our Elixar in fumo to flye.</hi>
                                 </l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <l n="1">1. <hi>Heark, do you hear, the Men cry Chimney ſweep;</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>Fanatick Wives will now no longer ſleep;</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>Strange Dreams of Religion have wak'd e'm by this:</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>In heat of their zeal</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>They'l preſently rail</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>At every thing is, and is not amiſs.</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l n="2">2. <hi>Be ſure if they ſee us, of Cuſtom they'l ſay,</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>We turn Day into Night, and Night into Day;</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l n="1">1. <hi>In this they are right;</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>We'd turn Day into Night;</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>But they lye, if they ſay,</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>That we would e're wiſh to turn Night into Day.</hi>
                                 </l>
                              </lg>
                              <stage>Chor.</stage>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>In this, &amp;c.</hi>
                              </l>
                           </div>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                  </q>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Bravely done, Boys; now to a little ſilent drinking: <hi>Town<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>love,</hi> you keep a good man from us.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>During the Catch</hi> Townlove <hi>and</hi> Roſe <hi>talk together.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le releaſe him preſently.</p>
                  <p>Faith, Sir, you ſee I have open'd my heart to you, in hopes to make you my Friend, for there is ſomething in your face pleaſes me ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tremely.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I am oblig'd to you by it, and ſhall as much ſeek to deſerve it; but me-thinks three hundred pounds a year is conſiderable to al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low you Miſtreſs, if you pay it conſtantly.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I never fail you may be ſure, whoſoever ſtays, ſhe muſt not. A dun between a pair of Sheets makes a man more impotent
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:101839:20"/>then a Witches tying of a Countrey Fellows Cod-piece-point.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, for my own part, I never underſtood the plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure of keeping Miſſes, I'm for othermens, if for any.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I believe your Friend is not of your mind; he, I perceive by his refuſing to drink, is for his Miſs; can you let me know who ſhe is?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Reſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Truly, Sir, I know of none he hath, he's Young, and ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther talks of Marriage then Miſſes.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, there's the miſchief on 't; he's new come from the Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſity, or I'le be hang'd; there's more of our hopeful Youth ſpoil'd by Schools and Univerſities then is imaginable; they learn nothing but to tread the dull paths of our Fore-Fathers, to bury themſelves alive in Marriage-Beds, to ariſe Monſters with huge Horns on their heads; if you have any kindneſs for him reclaim him from ſuch a deſign.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I have us'd my endeavours, and find him a little inclining to be kind to one <hi>Roſe,</hi> that waits on Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi>'s Siſter.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, Sir, I had rather he had a mind to be kind, as you call it, to my Siſter, and ſooner ſhould forgive him for it</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, Sir, what is ſhe to you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>She's one I have a mind to, and am reſolv'd if three hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds a Year will tempt her, ſhe ſhall be mine; provided, he, nor no other ſmock-fac'd Fellow hath been Quarter'd upon her afore hand.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>How'l you know that, if it is ſo?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>P'ſhaw, ne're ask queſtions of an Old Gameſter; and I'm reſolv'd, ſince my preſent Miſs is to be married, I'le purſue my de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign upon <hi>Roſe,</hi> to prevent yon ſmock-fac'd Fellow, of whom I have dreadful apprehenſions.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, trouble not your ſelf, I'le take care he ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>move his Siege.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Townlove,</hi> thou think'ſt we have nothing elſe to do but to talk; releaſe our man there, that you have taken Priſoner by the Ears.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, take him, but 'tis a thouſand pities he ſhould be ſpoyled by you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le warrant you, Sir, I am paſt their ſpoyling.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="35" facs="tcp:101839:20"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Gentlemen, I have perform'd my word with you; and ſo farewell.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Town.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Farewell; you have return'd us a better man for our preſent purpoſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you're in a rear, and ſince you allow drinking to be your profeſſion, you muſt balance Accounts, and pay down what you owe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le aſſure you, Sir, I am but juſt begun to be a profeſſor in the Myſtery, therefore, if you call for Debs too ſoon, you'l break me, and I ſhall ne're be able to follow the Trade, then let's now go on, I'le run in a rear no further, and the next time I meet you I'le balance Accounts.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, the Gentleman ſaith well, 'tis not our bus'neſs to be drunk, but to be merry; therefore, let's not break Methods at the preſent for any thing paſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>But, Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> by your leave I deſire no man to be a ſober obſerver of my drunken behaviour, therefore, if he and his Friend will not drink equally, I ſhould be glad of their rooms.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, as I take it, it was your own fault you had our Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies, and the terms we met on were agreed to before.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Not by me, I'm ſure.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Nor by me, therefore if you won't drink, turn out of the Company.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I muſt tell you this is rude, and no wayes becoming a Gentleman.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>How, Sir, what's that, Rude? La, la, la.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis ſtrange to ſee how men can ſee others faults, and be blind to their own; you tell Mr. <hi>Ruffle</hi> he's Rude for ſpeaking in his own Room, into which you intrude to controul him.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Alas, alas, the Gentleman's lately come out of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey, he doth not underſtand good breeding; la, la, la, poor thing.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Raſh,</hi> I can take more from you; but —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>But what; out with it, I'm your man, ne're look at him, and I muſt again tell you, that I believe you want good manners ſo to controul; here I ſay, theſe Gentlemen ſhall drink, or quit the Room.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:101839:21"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>And will, Sir, no fear; we do not at all hold our ſelves ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lig'd by Quarrelſom Company: Drawer, what's to pay?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Gentlemen, nothing for you; I am ſorry to have engaged you thus inconveniently, I'le aſſure you 'tis rare for me to ſee theſe things, eſpecially amongſt Friends.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>We thank you, Sir, and all others from whom we have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived Civility.</p>
                  <stage>[<hi>Exeunt</hi> Hon. <hi>and</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Damme, what's that, Civility? They deſerve to be kickt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>What, by you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>I, by him; and 'tis not you can hinder it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>No, by Heav'ns is it not, nor two ſuch, dear heart.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, if I ſhould tell you you lye, I'm afraid Mr. <hi>Raſh</hi> would call me rude, but I cannot forbear thinking ſo.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you provoke me to tell you, you're fit Company for Dogs and Horſes, and not for men, except 'tis your own Grooms, or'e whom you had beſt go and domineer in the Countrey.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you know my Obligations, or elſe —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Or elſe what?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Or elſe what? Poor thing: Or elſe what prethee? La, la, la.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Or elſe that.</p>
                  <stage>Throws a Pipe at him.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Damme, Blood, that; death and wounds, let me alone, nothing ſhall ſave him.</p>
                  <stage>Would draw, but is held.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, Sir, be as Valiant as you will, I'le ſwinge you if you be not quiet.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> the affront was meant to me; be quiet, Sir, we deſire no Quarrels here, and therefore you or I will quit the Room.</p>
                  <stage>Walks to and again in a great Rage.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>You pretend a right to it by the intereſt of your huffing Friend, therefore I'le quit it, And the World too, rather then take this.</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>— Sir, I'le ſee you at Home preſently. Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> have you no body to Exerciſe your ſetting out towards Valour upon but my Friends?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Friend me no Friends, I know no Friends in point of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, that's it I'le ſtick to.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Then I muſt tell you, Sir, you and I muſt not part before
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:101839:21"/>I carry my Friend ſatisfaction in your Blood, or loſe my own.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Will Merry,</hi> thou pretend'ſt to be a man of Honour, and place theſe things upon me, 'tis very well, I'faith, thou think'ſt now that I am not Valiant, and therefore pick'ſt a Quarrel, but it ſhan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not paſs, no, it ſhannot, for do what thou wilt, I will not fight with thee.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Then thou art a Coward ſtill, as rank a one as ever, and I loſe time to talk to thee.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Ay, think ſo, do; I a Coward, 'tis likely, dear heart.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Raſh,</hi> I hope to ſee you and Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> Friends ſoon.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſhall take little thought about it, ſo let's part; Good Morrow, Mr. <hi>Ruffle.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I, good Morrow; Huff me — Good Morrow, Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> la, la, la, huff me.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>The Scene a Chamber.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe <hi>in Man's Cloaths,</hi> Honour <hi>in a Night-Gown.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Ne're tell me on't, I'm confident ſome unlucky thing will happen, for I ne're perceiv'd my Brother more angry in my Life; I wiſh we had not gone.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I am rather glad we were there; for, knowing of the Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rel, we can take care to prevent the effects of it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>But we were the occaſions of it, you know.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Madam, I think not, for Mr. <hi>Raſh</hi> was in ſuch'a Quarrelſom humour, and that vapouring Gentleman did ſo puſh it on, that I am confident had not we been there the ſame thing would have hapned.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>One Knocks.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Who's there?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>within.</hi> Siſter, I would ſpeak with you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Immediately. 'Tis my Brother, what ſhall we do?</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:101839:22"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le ſtept into the Cloſet, and hearken, and then go down the back-ſtairs.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Roſe.</stage>
                  <stage>Honour <hi>opens the Door.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Siſter, ſince I left you, I have had more cauſe to conſider the conſequence of your marrying Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> then ever I had before, therefore I deſire to know what thoughts you have of him.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Truly, Brother, I cannot pretend an averſion to a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man you commanded me to favour as your Friend, and one you de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign'd I ſhould marry, though further I am no wayes engag'd.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I am glad to ſee your indifferency, for by this morning's work I find you can no wayes hope for that happineſs I once thought you might expect in being his; the Company he keeps is bad, and the conſequences will attend it muſt be worſe, therefore admit of no further addreſſes from him, which the better to prevent, you ſhall towards <hi>York-ſhire</hi> to morrow.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>To morrow, Sir?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>If ſo, 'tis time for me to beſtir my ſelf.</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I, Siſter, 'twill ſave you ſome bluſhes for ſo abrupt a break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with him, and I have hopes to live to give you full ſatisfaction for this change, and to beſtow you on one may more deſerve you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>The manner of your Diſcourſe doth much ſurprize me, and ſeems very myſterious; I hope there is no cauſe thoſe hopes you ſpeak of ſhould prove doubtful ones.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Siſter, I cannot tell, but I deſire, let things go how they will, that you'd prepare your ſelf for all may happen.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter a Servant.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, a Gentleman without deſires to ſpeak with you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Admit him in.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, your Noble proceedings in ſo Generouſly defending ſtrangers hath bound me for ever to your Service. And fearing leſt your Generoſity hath too far engag'd you in our behalfs, I am come to offer you the aſſiſtance of my Sword, thinking I ſhould but ill be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come the wearing it, if any other ſhould be drawn, and not it in my own Quarrel.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you are truly Noble, and I have juſt occaſion to give
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:101839:22"/>thanks to that unlucky Accident, ſince it produced me the Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaintance of ſo worthy a Perſon.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, your own demeanour is enough to inſpire worth into a Perſon that Naturally wants it, and if I have any, I ſhall impute it to the Example I received this day from you; but to avoyd Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plements, of which I am a bad returner, I beg you would employ me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, if I do, it ſhall be in an Office in which there ſhall on your part, be no hazzard: Siſter, I deſire you would entertain this Gentleman, whilſt I ſtep into your Cloſet to write a Letter.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, you can no wayes believe the great Obligations I have received this day from your Noble Brother.</p>
                  <stage>In a high voyce.</stage>
                  <p>But, Madam, not to loſe time, I will ſo mix my ſelf amongſt them, it ſhall be impoſſible, but I'le prevent all miſchief.</p>
                  <stage>Low.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>I, but the Countrey, and to leave Mr. <hi>Merry, Roſe,</hi> I am grown deſperate with the thoughts of it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Prepare your ſelf to go abroad, and leave the reſt to me.</p>
                  <stage>In a ſmall voyce.</stage>
                  <p>Madam, I dare aſſure your Lady-ſhip 'tis no ſuch matter; and upon my Honour, there is no man in the World ſhall be more careful of Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi>'s ſafety, then my ſelf.</p>
                  <stage>In a high tone.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>You ſeem a Gentleman to be rely'd on.</p>
                  <stage>Aloud.</stage>
                  <p>But, <hi>Roſe,</hi> if Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> ſhould be concern'd in the Quarrel after our leaving them, what then?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le warrant you, Madam, as I'le contrive the matter, he ſhall be better Friends with Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> then ever.</p>
                  <stage>Low.</stage>
                  <p>For truly, Madam, I obſerv'd nothing but a little heat about mine, and my Friends Intrution, that was all; and —</p>
                  <stage>Aloud.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland <hi>with a Letter.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I deſire you to deliver this Paper for me where 'tis directed; I beg your pardon for it's being Seal'd, ſince it is rather to rectifie ſome miſtakes between that Gentleman and I, then to pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſue them further, though, I confeſs, if he continues his reſentments, I had rather you were witneſs of them then any other Perſon wholly a ſtranger to their firſt beginnings.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I am proud that you are pleas'd to employ me any way: Your Lady-ſhips Servant.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:101839:23"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>But dear Brother, let me beg you, if any thing hath hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pened between Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> and you, that cauſes this ſuddain avertion, let me know it, that I may with Juſtice root out of my mind that little eſteem your Friendſhip to him, and his merit hath planted there.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>There is nothing, upon my word, Siſter, but my conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of this happineſs hath begot the change I have expreſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter Servant.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, here is a Letter, a Porter brought, he ſaith, from the <hi>Roſe</hi> Tavern.</p>
                  <floatingText type="letter">
                     <body>
                        <head>Muchland <hi>Reades.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <opener>
                           <salute>SIR,</salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>THE Injuries I received from you are unſupportable, nor can a man of Honour, as I profeſs, and ſhall ever teſtifie my ſelf to be, put them up; therefore, I deſire you would meet me ſingly with your Sword in your hand, at the lower ſide of <hi>Hide-Park,</hi> at ſix this morning, where I doubt not to make you know what it is to Injure the Valiant, and place abuſes upon the Worthy, in the firſt Rank of which I ſhall alwayes be ambitious, to have the Name ſubſcribed of</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Ruffle.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <p>'Tis dam'd unlucky this, I wiſh I had not ſent my Letter to be Chal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lenged to the ſame place whither I deſir'd Mr. <hi>Sharp</hi> to come; but ſtay, ſix of the Clock, this is an hour ſooner then I appointed, that's well; for if I be kill'd by this firſt, I ſhall dye the more con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentedly, in not having fought my Miſtreſſes Brother, and if I ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vive, I ſhall be in a condition to make good my word to him. Siſter, prepare for your Journey, and if you have any kindneſs for your ſelf, think not on Mr. <hi>Merry.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Not think of him, that's impoſſible; ſhould my Father's Soul riſe from the Grave, and bid me to forget him, I could not do it. No, Brother, his worth hath placed him here too faſt to be by ſmall diſlikes of yours remov'd.</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <pb n="41" facs="tcp:101839:23"/>
               <stage>The Scene a Tavern.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Ruffle, Fullam, <hi>and</hi> Breef.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Gentlemen, you have had your deſign upon me, what wou'd you more? We all know one another too. I believe that is not to place approbrious Names upon our own Qualities. I take you two to be men that will live, if Dice and Cards will do it; and I am confident you take me to be one that have no mind to leave a thouſand pounds a Year before. I muſt needs, and therefore am ſomething backwards in fighting matters.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>To ſpeak the truth, Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> I believe you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>And I.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Now I dare ſwear, if you would confeſs, there's neither of you love fighting any more then I do.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le aſſure you, Sir, my Reputation was never queſtion'd.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>That I believe, for like the ſubtle Squirrel, you fore-ſee where the Wind will be, and change your Neſt accordingly; but I have a plaguy damn'd humour of deſiring to be thought Valiant, which makes me provoke the beatings, I elſe might go without.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Then you deſerve them, Mr. <hi>Ruffle;</hi> but I am ſo wiſe, never to regard a beating I get by.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Gentlemen, to continue the good correſpondence our mutual knowing one another hath begun, I have a buſineſs to employ you in, which you effecting dextrouſly, will deſerve I ſhould make the ſum you have got from me already, a compleat hundred pounds.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Name it, Mr. <hi>Ruffle.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>And doubt us not.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I have ſent a Challenge to Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> who, I fear, will meet me: Now, if you two will watch him into the Field.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>And kill him for you, you'l give us twenty pounds.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>A very modeſt requeſt to begin Friendſhip with.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Troth, Sir, I have no mind to ſing doleful Ditties through a ſlip knot, not I.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:101839:24"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Nor have I any ambition to attain the Title of a proper Gentleman, as I Ride in Triumph on a two wheel'd Chariot.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir, as long as the Town is full of Gallants like you, that dare venture their thouſands againſt our nothings, we ſhall not be ſo diſtreſt, as to turn Bravoes.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Gentlemen, you run on apace, but 'tis all upon a falſe ſcent; why, I ne're deſir'd the Death of any Man in my Life, and wonder at thoſe they call Men of true Honour, that make no more of killing a Man for refuſing a Health, then I do to eat my Break-faſt: Yet, ſince the Town praiſes theſe hare-brains as Men of worth, I have a huge ambition to be thought one of e'm, ſo I could but obtain it without the danger of my ſelf or Antagoniſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay, if your deſign be bounded within the compaſs of hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man ſafety, I'm for you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>And ten pounds ſhall ne're be ſlighted by me, coming with the hazzard onely of a walk into the Fields.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Then Gentlemen, as I ſaid, dog him thither, and when we are both drawn, appear as taking his part againſt me, place it upon him, as if he had hir'd you; thus our Quarrel will end, and you ſhall have your money.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>If this be all, come away, we're agreed, I warrant you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>But carry it diſcreetly.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Ne're, ne're fear us; <hi>alone, alone, alone,</hi> come.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>The Fourth Act.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Raſh <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>SIſter, I proteſt his behaviour was unſupportable, he took upon him, as if he had had a right to domineer o're the whole Company.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="43" facs="tcp:101839:24"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis ſtrange, I never obſerv'd his tempet much to incline to Pride.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Not before you, but theſe Country Gentlemen are ſo us'd to controul by the vertue of being Juſtices, that what with their po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitiveneſs on one ſide, and their want of Breeding on the other, a Man had as good keep Company with a Conſtable in midſt of his Bill-men, as with one of them.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I am come to wait on you, a thing I ſhould not have omitted on my own account, though I now am here but as a Meſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger.</p>
                  <stage>Delivers him a Letter, which he reads.</stage>
                  <p>Madam, I beg your Ladyſhip's pardon for my interruption. Take that.</p>
                  <stage>Roſe <hi>gives her a Note privately.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>What ſhould this be? But I perceive it requires ſecre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſie.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I'le aſſure you for ſome reaſons, I had rather you had been the ſender then the bringer of this Letter, but however I ſhall perform it's Contents at the hour appointed.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I hope I am concern'd more then barely as a Letter Carrier, and ſince I know the moſt material buſineſs of it, I deſire you would ſatisfie my further Curioſity, I yet believing it is inten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded I ſhould make one at the meeting.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Not at all, I'le aſſure you, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis ſtrange, but I ſhall inquire the cauſe of it elſewhere. Your Ladyſhips moſt humble Servant.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt</hi> Roſe <hi>and</hi> Raſh.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>What Paper's this? <stage>(Reads)</stage> 
                     <hi>For Mrs.</hi> Elizabeth Raſh.</p>
                  <floatingText type="letter">
                     <body>
                        <head>Opens it, and finds.</head>
                        <p>MAdam, the Letter I deliver'd your Brother contains a Challenge to meet a Gentleman in Hide Park this Morning at eight of the Clock, I confeſs I muſt needs appear Treacherous, as well for opening the Letter, as for betraying the buſineſs, but when you ſhall know the true mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives that made me do both, I am confident you will not onely abſolve me, but allow a place in your eſteem for one who doth all he can to preſerve to you two friends; the loſs of either of which would be a perpetual trouble to you, and real grief to your unknown</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Servant.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <p>This requires care and Expedition to prevent, for the other Friend
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:101839:25"/>he means can be none but Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> I'le make a Viſit to his Siſter, and enquire out the matter.</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>Scene the Street.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Merry <hi>at one Door, and</hi> Roſe <hi>at the other.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you are well met; I was going to your Lodging to look for you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Troth, Sir, I am ſorry I am prevented the happineſs of meeting you there, we would have crackt a Bottle e're we had par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>It troubles me a little that I muſt tell you my buſineſs would ſcarce have provoked Drinking.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>But, Sir, let your buſineſs have been what it would, we would have drunk upon it: For if't had been good, 'twould have deſerv'd a Bottle; and if bad, needed one; and I tell you, Sir, I never ſaw any thing yet in my Life could put me paſt conſideration of a Bottle.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, the pleaſantneſs of your temper, with your Civilities to me and my Friend, makes me ſorry to tell you I am a Meſſenger from a Gentleman, to invite you with your Friend into the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> at Nine this Morning, to meet him that ſent me, and my ſelf; I need not name on what ſcore.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>No, no, 'tis to Fence for a Break-faſt of Honour, I gueſs the buſineſs well; let him be whom he will, he ſhall not fail of my Company, though I confeſs it ſeems very odd to be invited to a Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quet of Man's fleſh, without knowing a cauſe for the Treat. Pray Sir, the Name of this obliging Friend of mine.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Muchland,</hi> Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>How! Marry now I find a kind of a Qualm coming over my ſtomack, which makes me wiſh I could be excus'd on any terms, leſs then loſs of Reputation; yet faith I can't believe but you miſtake your Man, for I was juſt going to his Lodging to take up a Quarrel I fear'd might proceed too far between him and another.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:101839:25"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir, if your Name be <hi>Merry,</hi> you are the Man. He imputes the miſ-underſtanding between his Miſtreſſes Brother and him, to the Ill Company you drew him into, and therefore is re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd his Siſter ſhall into the Countrey from you to Morrow; and and he will have ſatisfaction for the injuries he receiv'd in the Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vern from none but your ſelf.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>A Compendious cauſe for a Quarrel, and much as ſigni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficant as moſt Duels now a days are fought upon: He receives the abuſes from others, and requires ſatisfaction from me, S'death, he might as well have plac'd it on the Vintner for keeping the Houſe, the Link-Boys for lighting him to it; or indeed on his Horſe that brought him his laſt Journey to Town, this Capriciouſneſs of his Temper with his deſign to take from me my Miſtreſs makes me wiſh he was here to begin preſently. Where's the place he deſigns for this dilicate Trial of Skill?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>In Hide-Park, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, I ſhall bring a Friend that hath as much cauſe of malice to you as this Man of Punctillioes hath to me, and therefore if you have no more wit, you may fight too.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I am not afraid to ſay I ſhall ſcarce be idle when I ſee you once engag'd.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>The Scene a Chamber.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Townlove <hi>and the Lady</hi> Turnup <hi>in Morning-Gowns.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>My dear <hi>Townlove,</hi> thou art the goodeſt Rogue for not Drinking, I could e'en bite thee to pieces for it. But faith I'le tell Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> on it ſoundly when I ſee him for keeping thee up all Night; come, prethee, ſhall we to Bed?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I preſently; but firſt you ſhall ſing me the new <hi>Scotch</hi> Song.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>No, prethee don't; I am ſo hoarſe with ſitting up for thee, that I ſhall never make any Muſick of it now, and I do ſo long to be in Bed, dear <hi>Townlove</hi> come, let's go.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="46" facs="tcp:101839:26"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I muſt have my Song firſt, time enough for Bed, we'l not Riſe till Dinner time, and that ſhan't be ready till three, that we may have time to go to the Play.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>And will you ſtay with me after the Play, and engage with no Body?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, my Song, and I won't.</p>
                  <q>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                        <body>
                           <div type="song">
                              <head>Song. 1.</head>
                              <lg>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>WIllie</hi> was ſo blithe a Lad,</l>
                                 <l>Nene like was in the Town;</l>
                                 <l>At <hi>Wake</hi> and <hi>Waſſel Willie</hi> had</l>
                                 <l>For Dancing chief Renown.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <head>2.</head>
                                 <l>He pick'd the Bar, and hurl'd a ſtean,</l>
                                 <l>Nea Man wou'd him out-gang;</l>
                                 <l>And if he ſtrave with any ean,</l>
                                 <l>He gard them lig alang.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <head>3</head>
                                 <l>But <hi>Willie</hi> needs would Wedded be,</l>
                                 <l>He lik'd ſo weele a Laſs</l>
                                 <l>That bonny was, and full of glee,</l>
                                 <l>And mickle all did paſs.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <head>4.</head>
                                 <l>Yet <hi>Willie</hi> was no ſooner Wed,</l>
                                 <l>But he full ſear did pine;</l>
                                 <l>He croſs'd his Arms, hang'd down his Head,</l>
                                 <l>And ſtill had watry Eyne.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <head>5.</head>
                                 <l>Ah, wea is me, would <hi>Willie</hi> ſay,</l>
                                 <l>That I am thus forlorn;</l>
                                 <l>I now can neither Dance nor Play,</l>
                                 <l>Nor ought but wind a Horn.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <pb n="47" facs="tcp:101839:26"/>
                              <lg>
                                 <head>6.</head>
                                 <l>The Lads and Laſſes all do laugh,</l>
                                 <l>And ſcorn me as I gang;</l>
                                 <l>They do me all a Cuckold knowgh,</l>
                                 <l>And gibe me with this Sang.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <head>7.</head>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>Willie</hi> ſoon muſt gang to work,</l>
                                 <l>Or <hi>Noone</hi> ſcodes him ſear;</l>
                                 <l>Maſs <hi>Johnne</hi> e're he wends to Kirk</l>
                                 <l>Mun con a point we her.</l>
                              </lg>
                              <lg>
                                 <head>8.</head>
                                 <l>Then <hi>Jocky, Sawny, Hugh,</hi> and <hi>Kit,</hi>
                                 </l>
                                 <l>
                                    <hi>Ralph, Wat,</hi> and many mere,</l>
                                 <l>Gang when they pleaſe, and take a bit,</l>
                                 <l>Whilſt <hi>Willie</hi> keeps the Whore.</l>
                              </lg>
                           </div>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                  </q>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter Maid.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Maid.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, here's Mr. <hi>Ruffle</hi> will not be ſatisfy'd without he can ſpeak with you; I told him you were aſleep, he ſaid, I muſt wake you, for it may be 'tis the laſt time he ſhall trouble you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>What doth the Coxcomb mean, to trouble me thus early? Tell him I value my Honour more, then to admit of a Man's Viſit at this time of Day; and ſay, I wonder at his Inſolence: Tell him any thing, rather then let him come up to diſturb my dear <hi>Townlove</hi> and I now.</p>
                  <stage>Exit Maid.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le hang'd if the Fool hath not run himſelf into ſome Quarrel laſt Night, and now comes to boaſt of his Valour; <hi>Will Merry</hi> was talking ſomething of it to me, but I ſcarce regarded what I did not believe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>What a pox is his Valour to me?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>But his thouſand pounds a year is; don't ſlight that.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>I, <hi>Townlove,</hi> you are weary of me, or elſe you would ne're put me upon Marrying that Fool.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Don't you prove your ſelf a worſe, in refuſing ſuch a For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune; you know my Eſtate is intail'd upon my Younger Brother, then ſhould I dye, what would you do for a maintenance? Beſides, can't I Viſit you then as I do now?</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="48" facs="tcp:101839:27"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>But will you, dear <hi>Townlove?</hi>
                  </p>
                  <stage>Enter Maid.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Maid.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, he will not be ſatisfied without ſeeing you; he ſaith, he had rather be ſo unhappy to dye in your diſpleaſure, then without taking his leave; I think he's mad, for he talks of nothing but Honour, Death, Victory, and the like.</p>
                  <stage>Exit Maid.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Go, bring him up; <hi>Townlove,</hi> ſtep into the Cloſet, we'l ſee what his mighty concerns are.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Ruffle <hi>and Maid; when he comes in, walks up and down, ſtamps, ſtarts, and buſtles.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Rufflle,</hi> I'le aſſure you your proceedings, in forcing your ſelf thus into my Chamber, hath given me high diſſatisfaction; you uſe me like one of the common things of the Town, that ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit of Viſits in their Beds; but I'le aſſure you I am none of thoſe: My Honour is dearer to me then my Life, and I'le not hazzard the loſs of my Reputation for the ſatisfaction of any Perſon Living.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>It can't be helpt, Madam, the Caſe is alter'd — I am not the Man you think me — no — The World's chang'd — <hi>Tempore Mutantur</hi> —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>The World's chang'd indeed; you have not dar'd to uſe me in this ſlight manner formerly, therefore, good Sir, your bus'neſs quickly, that you may be gone, and never ſee my face more.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>There's it, you'l prove a true Propheteſs I fear; but hang't, 'tis no matter, a Man muſt dye, and as good at firſt as at laſt. Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour; I, there's it, to dye, and lye in the Bed of Honour; who would deſire more?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Good Sir, be careful of my Honour, and if your bus'neſs be only to diſturb me, I command your ſpeedy abſence.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Command your Maids abſence, I ſhall tell you all.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>My Maid! Heav'ns forbid! A Man in the Room, and my Maid go out, not for the World! I believe you have ſome deſign upon me, and have ſet your Companions to watch their opportunity to enter when no body's here but us, ſo to force me to Marry you for ſafety of my Reputation; but I'le aſſure you I ſhall be more cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, your fears are vain — I adore you — And I dare tell you, I merit you now — ſince I am Valiant. You ſaid, you found my want of Valour the greateſt barr to my happineſs.
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:101839:27"/>Alas, alas, Madam, Cowardize was A humour I only put on for a time; but you ſhall hear ſuddenly ſuch things — la, la, la, — will you let your Maid with-draw? Upon my Honour, and by my budding Glory, I have no deſign, but to let you know I merit you — I merit you, that's a bold word, I gad, but I dare ſay it, la, la, la.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Peg,</hi> go down, but be ſure to be within hearing, ſhould I call.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Peg.</stage>
                  <p>Sir, you ſee what hazzards I run to give you ſatisfaction; I'm afraid you'l Interpret this to too much inclination in me, and I wou'd not that for the World.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, you need not fear cenſure for your favouring me, I tell you I deſerve it, for I am Valiant. You know <hi>Townlove,</hi> don't you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, Sir, what then?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>A very brave Fellow that — And <hi>Will Merry</hi> too; I have ſeen e'm both Viſit you — And brave Fellows both; by Heav'ns, Madam, they are, as any walks the ſtreets.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>I ne're heard otherways: But what then?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>What then? I ſay, damme, blood, ſhould any Bully Rock of e'm all but ſay, or think <hi>Townlove</hi> or <hi>Merry</hi> are not as brave Men as Live, I would ſend the lye down their Throats with my double fiſts, that I wou'd; <hi>Townlove</hi> or <hi>Merry</hi> not brave! I laugh at that, la, la, la.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>But good Sir, to the bus'neſs.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, that's to the bus'neſs, Madam, I tell you they are Gallant, Brave Fellows, and they know one ſhall be nameleſs, that's my ſelf, as brave as either of them, ask e'm when you ſee e'm, how I ſwing'd a couple of Bullys laſt Night; la, la, la. Ask e'm, I ſay, they'l tell you how I duſted e'm about when they were both drawn upon me at once; I feag'd e'm i'faith, they both ſaw it; two on e'm at a time, Madam, won their Money, made meer bubles of e'm, and when I had done, kickt e'm, and turn'd e'm down ſtairs; la, la, la, at the <hi>Roſe</hi> Tavern: How like you that, Madam?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Truly, Sir, I am glad you got no hurt, for I Love a Valiant Man and ſhould be ſorry he ſhould get hurt by his Courage. But, Sir, if this be all the bus'neſs, you might have ſtaid telling it till after Dinner.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="50" facs="tcp:101839:28"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>All, Madam, 'tis not half; this is only what <hi>Townlove</hi> and <hi>Merry</hi> ſaw: All, all, ſay you? Alas, alas, I am to Fight a Duel this Morning in Hide-Park, at ſix of the Clock, with a Man as Valiant as twenty ſuch as they, that's it: I tell you, Madam, this is truth, and therefore, not knowing how Fate will diſpoſe of this Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, I come to aſſure you my Soul is yours, go where it will.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>I find I'm over-come by your worth, it muſt not be, do not Fight; you ſay your Soul is mine, then do not take it from me, I will not let you Fight.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Alas, Madam, it can't be helpt — My Honour, my Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, think o'th' that; la, la, la, I tell you my Honour is dearer to me than my Life.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Or mine either I ſee; O cruel Man, was it with deſign to kill me you came this Morning? Alas, 'tis five a Clock already, and ſix, you ſay's, the hour. Oh, do not go, ſtay here with me, I'le ſay I lockt you up.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, 'tis all in vain, your tears are all in vain; my Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour calls me forth, if I be ſlain, as chance of War is doubtful, think ſometimes of poor <hi>Ruffle.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Ah, do not think of dying yet, do not go.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Honour, Madam, Honour; think of that: Farewel.</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>What the Devil doth the Rogue mean? Not one word of all his beating of two Men in our Company is true; he lay vapour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of his having kickt a Man, to <hi>Will Merry,</hi> and he believ'd it, but could not perſwade me to be of his Faith, though I believe there may be ſomething in the latter part of the Story.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Let him be hang'd, he is not worth concerning our ſelves about him, prethee Dear, let's to Bed.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay, I am confident he'l ſecure himſelf from any danger but dry beating, or kicking, and therefore he ſhall be no part of my care.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Peg.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Peg.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> muſt ſpeak with you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Bid him come up; what's his bus'neſs, I wonder?</p>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </sp>
               <pb n="51" facs="tcp:101839:28"/>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Merry.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Good Morrow, Madam. What, han't you been in Bed yet, <hi>Tow nlove?</hi> I ſee you mighty mannagers of Miſſes, that ſeem ſo induſtrious and eager to be at e'm are as long a getting into the Saddle when you have the Bridle in your hand, as Men leſs profeſt in the vaulting Trade.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Troth, Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> I could chide you heartily for keeping Mr. <hi>Townlove</hi> out all Night, when he had promiſed me he would come.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, you'l have greater Reaſon to chide, when I muſt take him from you preſently: Come, prethee <hi>Townlove,</hi> dreſs, I have buſineſs with you, your Ear —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>I wiſh, Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> you were Marryed once, then I hope you will be tam'd, and let Mr. <hi>Townlove</hi> ſleep in his Bed quietly.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I'm ſorry for it, I'le ſlip on my Coat; (help me, <hi>Peg,</hi>) and go with you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, Madam, I don't believe you wiſh his buſineſs ſhould be to ſleep quietly in Bed.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Troth, Sir, one good turn is, you ſcarce know what Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men wiſh.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>But, <hi>Will Merry,</hi> here hath been <hi>Ruffle,</hi> and told ſuch damn'd lyes to <hi>Turnup</hi> of his Valour, that you ne're heard the like; and quotes you and I for Vouchers.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Dam him, for an unreclaimable Coward, he did nothing but huff when you were gone, becauſe <hi>Ned Raſh</hi> ſeem'd to take his part; and when I believing him Valiant, would have took him to task, he prov'd the ſame ſneaking thing he always was.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>He tells me he is to fight this Morning at ſix.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, may be he might miſtake a Man, and give a Chal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lenge, but I'le ſecure him from fighting.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>There's ſomething comes in my Head; where are your Fiddles, <hi>Merry?</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>At the <hi>Roſe</hi> I left e'm, and bid e'm ſtay for me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Turnup,</hi> we'l ſend e'm to you, and give e'm ſuch Inſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, that 'tis ten to one they ſhall play up your Wedding Dinner to Day.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, dear <hi>Townlove,</hi> I had rather Live as I do.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="52" facs="tcp:101839:29"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, Girle, I like thee for this; refuſe a thouſand pounds a year for Love of a Raſcal, that will ne're Marry thee.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>I Love Mr. <hi>Townlove</hi> too well, to deſire to Marry him, if he was ſuch a Fool to have me; now all our pleaſures come freely, but when they once are our Duties, 'twou'd go ſo againſt the hair; no, I'le ne're marry a Man I Love.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>This is the prettieſt ſort of new Philoſophy in Love; right <hi>Deſcartes,</hi> it depends all upon motion. Why, what wou'd <hi>Lucrece, Cornelie,</hi> and the reſt of the Ancient Husband Lovers ſay; did they ſee theſe dayes?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, <hi>Merry,</hi> no doubt but they would be converted to Love for delight, and Marry for conveniency, as <hi>Turnup</hi> here ſhall do, therefore I charge you mannage your buſineſs ſo, as I may ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lute you the next time I ſee you, by the Name of <hi>Ruffle.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, <hi>Townlove,</hi> I did not think you would have left me ſo ſoon; but I will do what you bid me, to ſhew you that I can Love better than you in diſpoſing of my ſelf, that you may get a new Miſtreſs, for I know there's your aim.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>A gallant Trade, let me be hang'd elſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, let's away.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>The Scene a Chamber.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Betty <hi>and</hi> Honour.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Was e're ſo croſs a miſchief known? I'm confident Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> meant nothing but mirth.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>'Twas that untimely mirth, to which we owe all this di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtraction; Curſe on his Revels, and may he be condemn'd ne're to take Reſt that hath by this Nights waking, rob'd me, I fear, of quiet during Life.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Madam, me-thinks you are too paſſionate, and ſomething like your Brother, to whom in Juſtice you ſhould impute all miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chief that ſhall happen; for I'm ſure it was his onely fault theſe Quarrels ris.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis you are paſſionate, and blinded too by your concerns
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:101839:29"/>for <hi>Merry;</hi> he, I ſay, who, could he keep his Bed, and leave his Fooling, wou'd not be Author of ſo many broyls his drunkenneſs muſt daily now occaſion.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>This Language, Madam, better would beſeem your Land-Lady, when in a high concern for tother farthing Candle, ſhe wou'd rate your Foot-man for the evil hours he keeps. To tax a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man with Drunkenneſs, is proper for no mouth but ſuch a one as makes the loudeſt noiſe in crying Oyſters.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Oh, that we both were Men but for an hour, and all the Quarrel ours, though bound to end it with our Lives.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>I cannot wiſh to leave the World ſo ſoon, ſince there is ſomething in it I muſt like, in ſpight of all detraction. But truly, Madam, I could hazzard much againſt the Siſter of that Man I know attempts my Brother's Life.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Your Brother (Oh, that I live to ſay it) caus'd that Quarrel, as you do this; t'was he that ſent the Challenge.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis likely then, he had occaſion for it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Oh, yes, occaſion; he could not ſure want that, ſince I'm his Miſtreſs; one he fain would break with, and wants a fit pretence; but ſure he need not have gone ſo far about, for I believe he ne're had mighty cauſe to think I doted.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Madam, to deal freely, I've obſerv'd your Pride ſtill ſtrugled with your Inclination; yet had he not been blinded by his Paſſion, he might have ſeen through all your ſcorns a likeing.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Bet.</speaker>
                  <p>Ill-temper'd Maid, thus to abuſe my Patience: Oh, for two Swords, that Women, though we are, we yet might try whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther our feeble Arms were wholly wanting to our Active ſpleens.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Your wiſh ſo hearty ſeems, it wou'd be pity you ſhould not have it granted; and I find your braves have ſo diſperſt all fear in me, that I as much do long to try this fighting, as you can ſeem to do; ſtay but a little, I ſoon can find two Swords.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Hon.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Do't then, and if I don't ſoon make you feel th' effects of Anger, though by weakneſs backt, then let me be deſpis'd by all that Love me.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Honour <hi>with Swords.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Here are the Swords.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, give me one, I long to ſee it drawn.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay, ſtay, you ſhannot have the longeſt; there, take that.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="54" facs="tcp:101839:30"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Let me feel the point — 'tis ſharp, I warrant you I'le make it enter.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Enter where? I hope you do not mean to kill me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, come, lets fight; what, Weapons in our hands, and ſpend our time in talking.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe, <hi>and draws.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Hey day, what's here, two Women-Duellers? Some fighting Planet Reigns to day ſure: Ladies, 'tis very pretty, you that ſhould be Active in making Peace between your Brothers, are practiſing the Art to be their Seconds. Me-thinks a naked Weapon, with ſo ſharp a point, is not very proper for your Ladyſhips hand, pray let me take it from you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>I beg your pardon, Sir, 'tis not ſo eaſie to take a Sword from me, as you imagine.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>But I'le aſſure you, Lady, I muſt prevent all fighting, 'tis my buſineſs; therefore relate the Quarrel, that I may make you Friends.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>No Relations, Sir; our Quarrels Love and Honour, that's enough.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Enough, ſay you? I, to ſet the whole World together by the Ears, or to make e'm Friends again either: Love and Honour are the two great Wheels, on which all buſineſs moves. The Tradeſman Cheats you upon his Honour, and like a Lord ſwears by that, but that he particularly loves you, you ſhould not have it ſo. No Tragedy, Comedy, Farſe, Demi-Farſe, or Song now adayes, but is full of Love and Honour: Your Coffe-drinking-Crop-ear'd-Little Banded-Secretary, that pretends not to know more of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour than it's Name, will out of abundance of Love be ſtill ſighing and groaning for the Honour of the Nation. Nay, the Lady, that for Impudence ſake hides her Face behind a Vizzard, will proteſt in taking the mollifying Guinney, that it is not that, but the confidence ſhe hath that the Gallant will be careful of her Honour, and becauſe ſhe loves him, that makes her beſtow ſo conſiderable a Pox upon him: And therefore, Ladies, if Love and Honour be the motive of your unuſual Valour, 'tis ten to one you may do wonders with your Weapons without going to Fencing Schools.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, prethee, <hi>Roſe,</hi> leave Fooling, and tell us in what
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:101839:30"/>poſture our unlucky affairs are, for I am more for that, then for fighting.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Roſe,</hi> ſaid you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, the very ſame, at your Ladyſhips Service, though very unable, you'l ſay, to do much.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Prethee, how comes this Diſguiſe?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>To play the part of a right Town Gallant, raiſe Quarrels, and then prevent them by Diſcovery, this is the way moſt Men find to Honour now adayes; the Quarrel is begun with Son of a Whore, you Lye, or a box on the Ear, ſlight matters, not able to provoke heat of Blood enough to fight preſently, but the formal Challenge muſt follow, the Seconds muſt confer, and the Swords be meaſur'd in order to a meeting the next Morning in the Field; which none of the four but thinks himſelf bound by the Religious Rules of ſelf-pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervation to prevent, and therefore each whiſpers the matter to one of his beſt Friends at leaſt, and the Devil's in't, if none of them will find one that loves him ſo well to riſe a little earlier, to fetch a Guard to prevent all. And you muſt think they are ſoon made Friends, their meek Dove-like Honour being ſafe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>I never diſcover'd talking to be the Crime of our Sex be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore: I thought it had been a ſcandal placed upon us, but I ſee now 'tis true; for I never heard ſo many words to ſo little purpoſe from one that wore a pair of Breeches in my Life. Prethee, <hi>Roſe,</hi> leave this talkative humour, and tell me how matters ſtand.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, Ladies both, they ſtand as you would have e'm ſtand; therefore do but prepare your ſelves to go whither I will conduct you, if you are not throughly pleas'd with their ſtanding before to Morrow Morning, let <hi>Roſe</hi> be condemn'd never to have to do with any thing within a pair of Breeches again.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, <hi>Roſe,</hi> I will believe 'tis thy Morning's draught makes thy Tongue run thus wildly, pray heav'n it be'nt before thy wit.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>No fears, Madam, though I muſt tell you Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> has receiv'd a Challenge this morning as well as the reſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>He Challeng'd! By whom, dear <hi>Roſe,</hi> tell me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>No, I ſhould talk too much, ſhould I tell you; I will have a care of running into that error again.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Cruel Wench, to put me in a fright thus.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="56" facs="tcp:101839:31"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>I am glad to ſee you puniſht with your fears for <hi>Merry</hi>'s ſafety, me-thinks through all your ſcorns, was he but hear, he might diſcern a liking.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis true, I did deſerve your Anger, Madam, for urging that of which my ſelf was guilty; but pardon me, I hope this fal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling out will but confirm our Friendſhips.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>I doubt it not, if <hi>Roſe</hi> makes good her word.</p>
                  <stage>Throw away their Swords.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Why brave, i'faith, you're Bully Rocks exactly, and know to the ſplinter of a hair when to draw, and when to put up with Honour; Maſquerading muſt needs go on, when Women practice the ſubſtantial'ſt part of Man, that's drawing Naked Weapons. But come, a Coach waits at the Door to convey you where you may have opportunity to try your Courages a ſafer way, though I will not affirm without Blood-ſhed.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Thou art run ſtark mad, <hi>Roſe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>And we, I fear, are as mad, to believe any thing ſhe ſaith.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>But if you believe not me, go where you may truſt your ſenſes, I hope hearing and ſeeing, or at leaſt, the moſt excellent ſenſe feeling will be truſted by you.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>The Scene Hide-Park.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Ruffle <hi>alone.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>He is not come, I ſee; faith two to one he dares not: For I have ſeen many man with as fighting a Face, and as apt to throw a Tobacco-pipe too, that hath been as backwards when matters have come to the puſh as men of eaſier fleam; I, gad, I hope this will prove a lucky Adventure, but then I might have ſav'd the money I am to give <hi>Breef</hi> and <hi>Fullam</hi> for prevention; a plague on't, that we heartleſs men can't know one another by ſympathy, 'tis true, by ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perience on my ſelf, I can give a pretty near gueſs, and therefore I never hear a man that's apt to ſpeak ill of others behind their backs under the Seal of ſecrecy, or that enquires for mens Names that are Cowards, to report them ſo in all Companies they come in, or that
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:101839:31"/>is alwayes drawing a Sword, to talk of fancying a paſs, or that never ſees a pale, young, or ſickly Face, but he makes it red with bluſhing at the abuſes he puts upon it, or indeed one that ſeems alwayes ſo big with Valour, that by Hectoring, huffing, talking of Duels, and breaking Drawers pates, doth, as it were, cry out to be deliver'd of this Tympany of Courage — S'blood, what's that comes yon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der? By heav'ns my man — And no ſight of my hirelings — No where to get out of ſight till they appear — No, 'tis impoſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble but he ſees me: What the Devil ſhall I do — I think I had beſt fall to Queries about the Quarrel — a way many a Young Gallant hath prevented the pinking his Doublet by — Ne're ſtir, me-thinks the danger makes me think I dare fight; I, gad, I'le do't; hang it, it is but dying, and that I muſt do at laſt in ſpight of my teeth.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I ſee your Anger hath made you get the ſtart, both of the hour and me; 'tis hardly ſix.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Your provocation made it ſeem ſo to me an hour agone — and I do wonder —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Let's not loſe more time in talking then, the diſpatch I intend with my Sword ſhall make amends for the time you loſt by ſtaying.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I'm ignorant who is your Taylor, and therefore might enquire with what he lynes your Cloaths.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>You have reaſon, Sir, I think our Shirts an't proof.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I think we had beſt to ſtrip then, not that I doubt your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, Sir.</p>
                  <stage>Both ſtripping.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>That's as you pleaſe, Sir, it muſt relye on proof.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Sure I dare fight — the Spirit comes upon me: And this Gentleman ſeems ſo careleſs of it, that I believe there's not that dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger in ſighting I once thought — but wou'd the Rogues would come thought.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, are you ready?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Almoſt, Sir, a curſed Band-ſtring hampers my Button ſo, I can't undo't.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Shall I help you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir — Gad, they're coming —</p>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <pb n="58" facs="tcp:101839:32"/>
                  <p>I've done it, come, Sir; but what two men are yonder?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Some to prevent us, I dare lay my Life, they run ſo faſt; but let's make haſte, we may out-do their diligence.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I hope we may.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>They fight,</hi> Ruffle <hi>parries and traverſes. Enter</hi> Fullam <hi>and</hi> Breef.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Within.</speaker>
                  <p>Hold, Mr. <hi>Ruffle,</hi> you are a dead Man elſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, we beg your pardon, we came no ſooner to your Reſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cue.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>To</hi> Muchland.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>But we are glad our Swords were not wholly prevented from ſerving you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Gentlemen, what mean you to excuſe your abſence ſo long, ſince I could wiſh the courteſie had ſtill continued.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>We cannot blame you to be a little Angry, ſince we were not ſo diligent in performing our words as we promis'd.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>What words? What promiſe? Gentlemen, I never ſaw you before in my Life, as I know of.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>What, Sir, not at the <hi>Roſe</hi> Tavern this morning, when we engag'd our words to do you Service againſt this Gentleman, as we are ready, then let us uſe no time, for yonder's Company.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, give me leave to tell you, y'are both Villains, that would contrive the murder of my Honour, a thing much dearer to me than my Life; therefore, Sir, as you are a Gentleman, joyn, but and drive theſe Raſcals from our ſight, or from the World, and then we'l fight in quiet.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>To</hi> Ruffle.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Your Dialogue is too myſterious, Sir, for me to mix with; therefore ſtand off, if I'm ordain'd to dye now, none ſhall ſay I did not ſell my Life at Honours utmoſt rate, then do your worſt, this Tree ſhall guard my Back, and this my Face.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Sir, fall on, and let's diſpatch him quickly.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I'm here againſt you both: If you be Thieves, come, kill me firſt, then do the like by him, and take our plunder; but I am reſolv'd no fear ſhall let you take my Honour from me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, what do you mean? You carry things too far.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, do your worſt; why ſo long a joyning?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Oh heavens, what Fate is this?</p>
                  <stage>Enter Souldiers.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Officer.</speaker>
                  <p>Put up your Swords, and come along with us; muſt we be alwayes plagu'd with your raſh Quarrels?</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="59" facs="tcp:101839:32"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, as you're a Gentleman.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Officer.</speaker>
                  <p>No talking, Sir, to us; our Captain, perhaps, will hear you ſpeak.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="act">
               <head>The Fifth Act.</head>
               <stage>Scene the Park.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Sharp, Merry, <hi>and</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Sharp.</speaker>
                  <p>SInce we are met, I ſee there is a neceſſity of opening our minds one to another before we can part: Faith, ſay, is not your buſineſs fighting?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>I'm afraid it will prove ſo e're we go home, though con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidering every thing, I had much rather have walk'd abroad ſo early a Simpling, to gather herbs for a Dyet-drink, and took it when I had done, though it be the Liquor of all others I moſt abhor.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Sharp.</speaker>
                  <p>I muſt confeſs I am here on the like Errand, and ſhould be loath to be prevented, though how we ſhall ſave our Reputations to our ſeveral Adverſaries when they find us together, I am to ſeek; nor is it reaſon for either to deſire the Field, ſhould be cleared by the other.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le make a propoſition; you ſhall declare to each other the men you are to meet, then I will be upon the Scout, and give notice who approaches firſt, on which the other ſhall withdraw.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>I like the propoſition well; what ſay you, <hi>Merry?</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>The Gentleman I am to deal with, is one I would rather compoſe then fight with, and having little or no occaſion for the Quarrel, I hope to give Reaſons may end the buſineſs without noiſe, and therefore would be glad to ſpare Names.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Sharp.</speaker>
                  <p>There can be little occaſion for that caution, ſince, I ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe, we are all too much Gentlemen, to be thought bablers; and
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:101839:33"/>to ſhew I have reſerves, notwithſtanding I know your pretences; Mr. <hi>Merry,</hi> I dare tell you, 'tis Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> I ſtay for.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Muchland!</hi> By what motives do you ſtay for him?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Sharp.</speaker>
                  <p>Mov'd by a formal Challenge, ſent in writing, to meet him ſingly here: But who's your Man?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>I beg your pardon, I have reaſons force me to conceal his Name. But you ſurprize me much, and though I know that words went high between you, I ne're thought they could have mov'd a Challenge: Pray, Sir, who brought it?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Sharp.</speaker>
                  <p>Your cautious dealing teaches me the ſame, though, I con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs, too late.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I've no ſuch Obligations; and ſince I ſee there's ſomething foul in this, I will not ſpare to ſay, 'tis by Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi>'s appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment we are likewiſe here now; and I am ſorry to ſee, that Chal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lenging two Men together to one place, his Courage dare meet neither.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Townlove,</hi> don't wrong a Man you never try'd.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>He that ſeeks further tryal let him find it, I'm ſatisfied, if words will fright a Man, he ſhan't want them from him; but pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thee tell, what Man did bring thy Challenge?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Sharp.</speaker>
                  <p>One of thoſe Gentlemen we met i'th' ſtreet; he that durſt drink.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>The ſame that came to me; 'tis plain, they do but Jeſt, and ſent us hither only to laugh at us.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>My Temper's not ſo pleaſant to find out Jeſts in formal Challenges.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Nor mine ſo ſowr, but I can take for Jeſt all that is meant ſo.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>All that occurs to me on the whole matter, is this, that we may all go back again, and wait his Explanation of the Riddle.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter a Guard.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Officer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Gentlemen, deliver up your Swords, you'l have no uſe of e'm, it ſeems, to day.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>I pray Sir, what's the matter?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Officer.</speaker>
                  <p>We are ſent to prevent the Duel you are come about.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>It ſeem we came about no Duel, Sir, and you may ſpare your pains.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="61" facs="tcp:101839:33"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Officer.</speaker>
                  <p>You are merry, Sir, but we muſt do our Duty; then give us up your Swords.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Where is it we muſt go?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Officer.</speaker>
                  <p>The back way to the Mulberry-Garden; they who em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy'd us wait our coming thither: But we want another, they ſaid we ſhould find four.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>It was a needleſs caution in e'm, be who they will; for that fourth man you ſpeak of is as good as forty Guards at preven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting Duels.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, go on, we'l be your Peaceful Priſoners, though you permit our Swords.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Officer.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, 'tis enough; march on.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>The Scene Mulberry-Garden.</stage>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Honour, Betty, <hi>and</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I am ſurpriz'd extreamly, here is a Guard hath brought in four Gentlemen already they took Actively fighting, as they ſay, and Mr. <hi>Muchland's</hi> one, I ſaw him through the Door.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>This is your diligence, good Mrs. <hi>Roſe,</hi> you have undone us, for if they've fought, they then will ne're be Friends.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>What a Fool was I to truſt ſo weighty a concern to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duct of a wanton, hare-brain'd Wench.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Ne're ſtir, <hi>Roſe,</hi> compoſe all matters, as you promis'd, or you ſhall find what 'tis to raiſe my expectation high, and then to fool me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>'Tis not your wanton Jeſts ſhall bring you off, I'le ſwear you ſhan't Live with me a day longer, if you fail your promiſe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Hey day, will you but give me leave to ſpeak; you're as pettiſh both of you as two Puritan Siſters, condemn'd to dye Maids, the greateſt Curſe accounted by the Saints of our Reformation that can be.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:101839:34"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>What can you ſay? Flam us off with ſome untoward Jeſt; no, forſooth, that ſhall not ſerve your turn.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I don't intend it ſhall, have but patience, that I may go and mix in Company with theſe ſame Duellers, if I don't ſet all things right again, let me be diſcarded by your Ladyſhip, and bound to fight a Duel with yours.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Let's ſee the effects of your promiſes quickly, or the Duel you ſpeak of may prove a ſharper then you believe.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>If the Guard I have ſent out catch any Quarry, let them keep e'm cloſe in ſome Room till I return.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>It ſhall be done, but let us have no more failings on your part.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland, <hi>firſt Officer,</hi> Fullam, <hi>and</hi> Breef.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>By a Woman's directions, it ſeems, you ſurpriz'd us, and ſhe's a Friend of <hi>Ruffle</hi>'s.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>1. <hi>Officer.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Yes, Sir, and they're together; I believe they will Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, for a Parſon is ſent for.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>You ſeem a Man of Reaſon; your Ear.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>This <hi>Ruffle</hi> will cheat us of what he promis'd, for he told me juſt now we came too late, and that the danger was paſt, he be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing forced to fight e're we Reliev'd him.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>He curſt and ſwore when I but ſpoke to him, and told me he would have me toſt in a Blanket if I but mention'd money to him. Nay, he ſwore damn him, if in the humour he was in, he could not have beat us all three. And I believe he is Valiant, for we, you know, found him ſtript and fighting.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>But he parryed and traverſt damnably faſt, and I'm convinc'd by Experience, that all Men who draw Swords are not Valiant; and that the Diſeaſe of Cowardiſe, when once proof againſt the Phyſick of beating, as his oft hath been, is incurable.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>I cannot tell, but if we were once well off with what we got to Night, I would forgive him my Mornings hire.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>I'm of your mind for that, I could admit of an eaſie excuſe to be going.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>1. <hi>Officer.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you have ſatisfied me, and 'tis but reaſon; I'le take care you ſhannot be diſturb'd.</p>
                  <stage>Exit Officer.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Gentlemen, my Old Acquaintance, and very good
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:101839:34"/>Friends that I never ſaw before, what motives had you to uſe me as you did i'th' Field juſt now?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Uſe you, how did we uſe you? Were not we civil in taking of your part? Damme, what wou'd you be at?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>No huſſing, Raſcals, that will not do with me, I'm none of thoſe — Come, tell me preſently what made</p>
                  <stage>Draws.</stage>
                  <p>you intereſt your ſelves in my concerns with ſuch a lye to back it, as if I had employ'd you? Come, Sir, ſpeak.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Very pretty: <hi>Breef,</hi> didſt ever ſee the like? The Gallant knows us both for men of Honour, he durſt not elſe provoke two of us thus.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Men of Honour i'th' Devils Name: A pair of Curs in couples are not more tame, nor readier for a beating; you huffing Raſcal, anſwer, what made you do't?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>This is unſufferable, I am a Gentleman, and therefore do require ſatisfaction for this abuſe; meet me ſingly with your Sword then to morrow morning at the place where I ſav'd your Life and Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour both to day.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Town tricks right; I'le try you firſt how far a Cudgel will provoke your paſſion.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Muchland, <hi>and bolts the Door.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>What ſhall we do, he hath lock'd the Door, or elſe we might have got <hi>Ruffle</hi> to take our parts.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, let's both draw, and try to keep him off till the Guard hears.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Hang't, that won't do; I ſee he's one of thoſe that count their Honour dearer then their Lives; and Hell, Damnation, the Devil and all are not able to fright them from fighting when they are ſet on't. And though by my manner of Living I ſhould fear Hell as little as any Man, yet I could never perſwade my ſelf to be ready to dye, neither by Sword nor Hanging, one of which uſually fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows the fighting of Men that Live in publick fame as I do.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Why then let's reſolve to ſuffer bravely, 'tis but a beating he'l give us, and he'l ſoon give over the Cudgel, if he be a Man of Honour as thou think'ſt he is.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>I, but he is a Man of Countrey Honour, and they go a great way farther in beating a Man then your City Man of Honour doth. Alas, I know e'm both, the one is contented to give the
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:101839:35"/>ſingle Battoon of diſgrace, but the tother ne're thinks it enough till he makes your skin o'th' colour of your hair. I am for down-right confeſſing all.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>That's worſe by half, for then we fall under the Revenge of <hi>Ruffle,</hi> and nothing like being in the power of an inraged Coward.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland <hi>with two Cudgels.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>He comes, oh, heart, heart, hold breaking.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Gallants, I ſhould be loath to make uſe of theſe edgeleſs Weapons, therefore confeſs, and ſave me and your ſelves the trouble.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>S'death, Sir, I hope you do not intend to be rude to Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men in Cuſtody; you know we are Priſoners, or elſe —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Or elſe you would run away, therefore I'le begin with you.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Beats</hi> Fullam.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>What do you mean, Sir — Damme, this muſt not paſs — Revenge muſt follow — aſſure your ſelf it muſt —</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I do conſider that, and will give you a little thinking time, whilſt I exerciſe your Comerade.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Good Sir, be civil, you know I han't gave you a word to diſpleaſe you.</p>
                  <stage>Beats him.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Confeſs, Sir, then; confeſs.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Hold, good Sir, and I will.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful</speaker>
                  <p>Cowardly Raſcal; what, doſt fear a beating?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Pray valiant Sir, ſtand by: Come, Sir, your ſtory.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, we were hir'd by Mr. <hi>Ruffle</hi> to come into the Field, and ſeem to take your part, to get him Honour.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>What ſay you, Sir? Is this ſtory true?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes, 'tis a truth, but I'd have ſooner dy'd then told it you. Out, you hen-hearted Coward.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Go, Sirrah, and kick him for calling you Coward.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, I wou'd he durſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Do't, or I'le Baſtinado you again.</p>
                  <stage>Breef <hi>takes up a ſtick, and goes to beat</hi> Fullam, <hi>who takes up another, and worſts him.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, I'le teach you to ſtrike me, you Cowardly Rogue.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>So, well done; now we ſhall ſoon be Friends.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Friends, Sir; no, Gad, I'le no Friendſhip with you.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="65" facs="tcp:101839:35"/>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter firſt Officer and</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>1. <hi>Officer.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>This Gentlemans importunity hath forc'd me to intro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce him to you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>He's truly welcome.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I am much ſurprized to find you here.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>You have reaſon for your wonder, but will not have ſo long, when I ſhall tell you the cauſe of my ſurpriſal, but now I have not time, I muſt deſire you to haſte into the Park to find out Mr. <hi>Sharp,</hi> and bring him hither, my Honour elſe may ſuffer.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſhall obey you, and return preſently.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, my moſt excellent brace of Spanniels, you muſt go and witneſs what you've ſaid.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le witneſs nothing, not I.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>1. <hi>Officer.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Come, Sir, no muttering, march.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Honour, Betty, <hi>and ſecond Officer.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>2. <hi>Officer.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>The Gentlemen we have taken, call themſelves <hi>Raſh, Merry,</hi> and <hi>Townlove.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>You have done well; keep e'm upon your Lives.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>2. <hi>Officer.</hi>
                  </speaker>
                  <p>Ne're fear it, Madam, they are ſafe enough.</p>
                  <stage>Exit ſecond Officer.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>We're ſure by this 'tis none of them that fought with Mr. <hi>Muchland.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>No, that matter's plain, and I begin to gueſs the Man; but here comes <hi>Roſe</hi> will tell all. Oh, excellent <hi>Roſe,</hi> thy Guard of new made Red-Coats have done their buſineſs bravely; they've brought in <hi>Merry, Raſh,</hi> and <hi>Townlove.</hi>
                  </p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I, now 'tis excellent <hi>Roſe;</hi> but by and by you'l call me long<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tong'd, ſhallow-pate again: I am ſo elevated with the ſucceſs of my buſineſs, that like a new-made Biſhop, I could appear extreamly grave and moody.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay, <hi>Roſe,</hi> no ſtop of thy Induſtry for this favour of For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune, for ſhould ſhe frown again, thy condition, like a diſgrac'd Favourites, would be more ſubject to oppreſſion, then if never ſhe had ſmil'd upon thee.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I'faith, I believe you, for 'tis not the well-contriv'd project, but the ſucceſsful one is commended; and therefore I'le go on to projection. Step into that Cloſet there.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt</hi> Betty <hi>and</hi> Hon.</stage>
                  <p>Officer, bring in your Priſoners.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="66" facs="tcp:101839:36"/>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter ſecond Officer, with</hi> Raſh, Merry, <hi>and</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               <p>Gentlemen, you are welcome to the Mulberry-Garden.</p>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>You'l have our thanks, Sir, as we find our uſage.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>It cannot well be worſe then what I ſuffer'd at our firſt meeting, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, to the buſineſs, Sir; what wou'd you with us?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>By your demand you almoſt make me think I am your Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoner, but I muſt have other Language from you e're we part.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, you need uſe little ceremony in what you mean to do; your Souldiers, if you command them, took us in the Field, you know as well as we why we were there.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>And there may come a time you may account for it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>No threatning, Sir, for you are leaſt concern'd, and ſince I am reſolv'd to examine you apart, you ſhall be the firſt I'le talk with. Officer, put that Gentleman into that Room,</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Puts</hi> Merry <hi>in to</hi> Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <p>take that along with you, and leave this angry Man for me to talk with.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt all but</hi> Roſe <hi>and</hi> Townlove.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, and what's all this for?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>You told me once to day, you wiſht my Friendſhip.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I did ſo, when I took you for a Man of Honour, but now I ſee you're none, I ſlight your Friendſhip.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>In what don't I appear the ſame Man ſtill?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>You carry Challenges baſely intermixt, and yet prevent all ſighting by making us Priſoners, and uſe us too as't 'twere for Crimes of State we were Committed.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>High accuſations, and with much Anger urg'd; but ſuppoſe <hi>Roſe</hi> ſhould like the propoſition you made her to day, and that I had been the main Inſtrument to bring it about, would you not be pleas'd with me then?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>No, ſaith, ſhould I not; for I believe if ſo, ſhe's but your leavings, and I d be loath to keep her on thoſe terms.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I will not ſay, but I know whether <hi>Roſe</hi> be a M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n or a Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man: But what then? I dare be ſworn for her <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o Man elſe doth; then why ſo coy? I do believe you have kept <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mendations.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>That's no matter, I took e'm from better Friends then; but to the buſineſs, Sir, and then diſmiſs me.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="67" facs="tcp:101839:36"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>You're at the buſineſs now; I'm <hi>Roſe</hi> her ſelf.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>The Devil thou art; but now I look on thee better, 'tis thee; but what Gallant was he with you, <hi>Roſe?</hi> I'm afraid you are pre-ingaged.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>It was a Woman too; no mote of that, I'le tell you all anon: Why an't you ſuricus, appoint the place to meet in for our Duel? I know you'l Challenge me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>I, to a Bed, dear <hi>Roſe;</hi> that, that's the place we'l meet in.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Soft and fair, two words more to that bargain; your pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent buſineſs is to take up Quarrels, for Mr. <hi>Merry's</hi> is ended I do believe by this; don't ſeem to know me, not nothing of the frolick to my Lady, as you love me; ſhe's here, and <hi>Raſhes</hi> Siſter with her.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland, Ruffle, Breef, <hi>and</hi> Fullam.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Upon my Honour all they ſay is falſe, and you may think ſo by what they've done: Take beaten Raſcals words, they ſpeak for fear.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I would be glad to think ſo.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>And I'le convince you preſently; lend me your Cudgel.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>He goeth to beat</hi> Fullam.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>What do you mean, Mr. <hi>Ruffle?</hi> As I'm a Gentleman, do what he could, I never would confeſs.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Then was it you that ſaid it, Villain?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>I muſt confeſs my frailty; it was I.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Oh, was it ſo?</p>
                  <stage>Beats him.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>But he confirm'd it too.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Then he ſhall have it too.</p>
                  <stage>Beats tother.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Hold, hold, good Sir, hold.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Did I then hire you to it?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir, I ſay, and ſwore it too before.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>What ſay you, Raſcal?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Truly I cannot tell; I think you did not.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>You ſee what Rogues are here.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I'm ſatisfied, and therefore let e'm go.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt</hi> Fullam <hi>and</hi> Breef.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>What do you mean, Sir?</p>
                  <stage>Muchland <hi>locks the Door.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </sp>
               <pb n="68" facs="tcp:101839:37"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>To end this matter now, and ſince theſe Rogues have plac'd a ſcandal on you, wipe it off; come, to your Sword.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I'm new Married, and will not fight to day.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Oh, the multitude of ſeveral ſorts of Cowards there are in the World! Come, without more ado, confeſs your ſelf one.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Confeſs my ſelf a Coward, that's pretty, i'faith; have not you ſeen me meet you in the Field, Fight you, beat theſe Raſcals for traducing me, and yet confeſs my ſelt a Coward, becauſe I don't think it proper to fight on my Wedding-day? A very modeſt pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition. No, Sir, I'd have you know, this is a day of Joy, I have Marryed a Lady worth thouſands, beſides, for Beauty, Virtue, and good Breeding, I'le defie you to match her between the Tower and Weſtminſter-Hall. She it was, that hearing of our Quarrel, ſent the Guard to ſurprize us; and ſhall I wrong the Love of ſo Excellent a Lady for your humour? Damme, Blood, you make me mad that you do.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I wiſh I could ſee the effects of it, but not to ſpend time in words, the caſe is this; either confeſs you hir'd thoſe Fellows to come into the Field, that you likewiſe told your Wife that now is, of the Quarrel on purpoſe to be ſurpriz'd, and that you are a Coward, and dare not fight. And all this to be openly done before as many as I ſhall appoint to hear it, or prepare your ſelf to dye, for that muſt be your Fate or mine before we part this Room.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Tell me, Sir, do you think you Act now like a Man of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour — Heav'ns, how Men miſtake themſelves; would you place this upon a Man that you thought durſt fight? Tell me that, would you?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Sir, I ſhould not.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>there's it, and yet you hope to be counted a brave Man for this — Damme, Blood, if I could not find in my heart to break my Reſolution of not Fighting to day, rather then ſuffer you to go away with it thus. But ſince my word was paſt before for not fight<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing (and 'tis the greateſt part of Honour to keep that) I will hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mour you in tother: But, Sir, let it be done ſo, that it may not grieve my Wife; and write down the words that I muſt ſay, that there may be no new occaſion for breach of Friendſhip between you and I.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="69" facs="tcp:101839:37"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, Sir, I ſhall do it. Who waits there?</p>
                  <stage>Opens the Door.</stage>
                  <p>Bring a Pen and Ink to the next Room.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I have perform'd your Commands; the Gentleman is in another Room.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>He ſhall ſoon ſee the occaſion of my failing him.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Muchland.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, your moſt obedient Servant, you are a Friend of Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi>'s here; upon my Life a worthy Man he is: He and I have been merry together this Morning.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>By the Guard that waits, I thought it had been otherways.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>You mean, you thought us fighting; but that hinders no mirth, Men of Honour never fall out about that — though I could tell you, as a Friend of his, I was once deſperately afraid I had kill'd him.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>Why, did you Wound him, Sir?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>No, but I'le tell you, he ſtood upon his Guard, as't might be thus; and to ſpeak truth, would not budge one foot, I'le ſay that for him; I made a paſs or two, as't might be thus; he parryed, but I reſolv'd to make an end on't quickly, ſeeing ſome People coming, therefore I made a through paſs, and run my Sword to'th' hilts.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>In what?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>In's ſhirt, it prov'd to be in's ſhirt; but I, Gad, I was upon flying, if the Guard had not come and took us.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>It ſeems there was no cauſe, having done him no hurt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I knew not that; but I Gad, he's your Friend, preſerve him ſo, for there breaths not a braver fellow, take that from me. But, Sir, upon your Honour ſpeak not a word of this, I know he'l have you Spectator of a frolick we have agreed on; 'tis that I will not have confidence to ſpeak ſome words openly that he ſhall write, but I Gad, let e'm be as bad as they will, I'le ſpeak e'm, let who will be by.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>There are the words, look e'm over, I'le tell you when to ſpeak e'm.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Then if I do it not, take me and hang me.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <pb n="70" facs="tcp:101839:38"/>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Merry, Townlove, Honour, Betty, <hi>and</hi> Raſh.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>Yes truly, Sir, the Gentleman that brought you the Chal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lenge gave me notice of it, and had I not Reaſon to take the beſt care I could to prevent it?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>They took care enough themſelves, it ſeems.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Faith, <hi>Raſh,</hi> I had once as ill an Opinion of their procee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dings as you, but now I am fully ſatisfied in every particular.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>I am glad I out-went you both in true conſidering, for you know it would never out of my head, but that <hi>Muchland</hi> was all worth. Oh, the Excellent Advantages Men have by Wine! it leaves a certain Spirit in ones head, like that of Propheſie.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Like it indeed; Propheſie being a ſort of madneſs, that fills the head, and intoxicates the Underſtanding, making Men ſpeak abundance of things they neither believe themſelves, nor any Body elſe, till ſomething comes to paſs by chance that they ſeem'd to fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tell. And then oh, the wonder, as if they that fore-told what could not be prevented, were not altogether as uſeleſs Members to a Common-Wealth, as a ſick Paſſenger at Sea is to a ſinking Ship, when he bellows out between Praying and Swearing; God, we are all loſt.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Prethee leave, I'm for no Morals, or long-winded ſimelies. Here comes the Lad I am for.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Roſe.</stage>
                  <p>One that underſtands his Glaſs, and makes himſelf and his Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny merry without detracting from his abſent, or ſatiriſing on his preſent Friend.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, our little Projecter, how go matters? I could for thy ſake turn Woodcock in the Play, and alwayes be kiſſing.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Kiſſes</hi> Roſe.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>If you ſtop my mouth thus, how ſhall I tell what you would know: But are you all agreed upon the matter?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>Onely <hi>Ned Raſh</hi> hath a little grumbling diſcontent towards you ſtill.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>I ſhall ſoon Cure that; come, you muſt go all of you to the Balcony, and there you ſhall ſee what Heroes Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> hath been engag'd withal this Morning. And, Mr. <hi>Raſh,</hi> if your Siſter do not make Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> and you, and I too Friends, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore we part, I'le be condemn'd to ſing Fortune my Foe in a Nunnery all dayes of my Life.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="71" facs="tcp:101839:38"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>In a Nunnery! What have you to do with a Nunnery?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>You ſay right indeed, for if the bargain go on you wot on, I ſhould have little to do with a Nunnery, though I were condemn'd to wear Petticoats; but no more of thoſe miſtakes, but away.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>Enter</hi> Muchland, Ruffle, Fullam, Breef, <hi>firſt Officer, and Guard.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> the words are too ſevere, there is no enduring of e'm — let me leave out this Sentence: <hi>And like a Cowardly Son of a Whore as I am:</hi> Look you, Sir, this is abuſing of my Mother, and ſhe had not the leaſt hand in the Quarrel. What ſay you, Sir, is not this Reaſon?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Gad, Sir, I wou'd ſooner dye then ſay it.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>You'l ſooner be hang'd then dye, like a Cowardly Raſcal as you are.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>You may ſay what you will, but there are them in Town know me for another ſort of Man I dare aſſure you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Then the Song, Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> you know that goeth be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yond the bargain.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter on one ſide all the Company, and</hi> Turnup.</stage>
                  <p>What, all them, and my own dear Wife too. By Heav'ns I'le dye ten thouſand Deaths before I'le do't. Your Servant, Gentlemen; your Servant, Ladies. A merry Craſh hath hapned between Mr. <hi>Muchland</hi> and I; we are here Drolling one upon another: Gad, Mr. <hi>Muchland,</hi> if you had not the ill Nature of all the Juſtices in your whole Countrey, you would never urge me to it, I never will conſent to read the Paper, and ſing the Song too, that's flat.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Well, on condition, you'l all of you ſing, and Act the Song to the Life, I am contented you ſhall only deliver the Paper to Mr. <hi>Raſh,</hi> and confeſs it to be all a truth.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le do't, here's my hand on't; Mr. <hi>Raſh</hi> is a worthy Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman, and knoweth me well enough: Come down, come down, I and theſe Gentlemen are to ſing a mad Song to you.</p>
                  <stage>Exeunt above.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>He that ſpares, either in kicking or cuffing, ſhall find me upon his back with this.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Damme, if either of you kick, or ſtrike me hard, I'le ſwinge you when we have done.</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Aſide To</hi> Ful. <hi>and</hi> Breef.</stage>
               </sp>
               <pb n="72" facs="tcp:101839:39"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le warrant you, Sir.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>I'le do as I ſee cauſe: <hi>Breef,</hi> have you a care of my Boyl you had beſt, or look to't.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>Enter all below.</stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I hope this Gentleman hath inform'd you with what reſentments I intended to repair my Reputation, which I look'd upon as too deeply wounded for your ſelf to excuſe my ſilence in it, and likewiſe by what unlucky Accident I was prevented performing my appointment.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, I've no cauſe left to doubt i'th' leaſt your Honour, and do confeſs I was to blame in preſſing you too far; for which I beg your pardon.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Could I but hope this Ladies, you have mine.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>Ne're fear it, Brother, we are both come thus far to be Married, if we had your conſent, for I confeſs I am loath to go in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the Countrey, and leave Mr. <hi>Merry</hi> unreclaim'd, for fear he ſhould be occaſion of ſome further Quarrel between you two.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>What ſay you, Madam, will you make good her word?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                  <p>I to my Brother, Sir, refer the matter.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Raſh.</speaker>
                  <p>Then you are his; take, Sir, this Bond of Friendſhip.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>A Chain ſo ſtrong, I hope can never break. Siſter, I wiſh you happy in your Choice.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Friends all, Friends all; why, this is fine i'faith: Now, <hi>Muchland,</hi> hang the Catch; come, paſs it by.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>Not for the World: Come, the Wine there, and begin.</p>
               </sp>
               <stage>
                  <hi>A Catch Sung by</hi> Ruffle, Breef, <hi>and</hi> Fullam: <hi>They in their turns, Drinking, Kicking, and Cuffing one the other at the words to that purpoſe.</hi>
               </stage>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruffle.</speaker>
                  <l>
                     <hi>WE are Gallants of the Town;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Men of ſprightly Breeding:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>If Oaths will do't, we run e'm down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But never come to Bleeding.</hi>
                  </l>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Chor.</speaker>
                  <l>
                     <hi>We meaſure Swords, appoint the place, and thither do repair too;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But Drink, Huff, Kick, Cuff; this is all we dare do.</hi>
                  </l>
               </sp>
               <pb n="73" facs="tcp:101839:39"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Fullam.</speaker>
                  <l>
                     <hi>At Play-Houſe we do count it brave</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>To have the Maſques Acquaintance;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>'Gainſt Wit and Sence we alwayes rave,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And call't inſpid Non-ſence.</hi>
                  </l>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Chor.</speaker>
                  <l>
                     <hi>We meaſure Swords, appoint the place, and thither do repair too;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But Drink, Huff, Kick, Cuff; this is all we dare do.</hi>
                  </l>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <l>
                     <hi>In Coffee-Houſe we Battles fight,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And cenſure men of Honour;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>We ſwear that ſuch a Ladies right,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And hath a Clap upon her.</hi>
                  </l>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Chor.</speaker>
                  <l>
                     <hi>We meaſure Swords, appoint the place, and thither do repair too;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But Drink, Huff, Kick, Cuff; this is all we dare do.</hi>
                  </l>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>That's done like Men of Valour.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Nay, Gad, I defie him that can ſay I fear.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Turn.</speaker>
                  <p>Now you are all Friends, know, the Guard I made uſe of to ſecure you, are all Mr. <hi>Merry</hi>'s Fiddles.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>I'm glad I did not know ſo much before, I ſhould have broke their Priſon, or their pates.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>My Guard are ſomething a Kin to yours, Men very expert in handling their Feet, if a Man may ſay ſo.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>All this I ſee is a meer contrivance for a Dance; let's, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any more ado, have it then.</p>
                  <stage>Dance.</stage>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Come, Gallants, you think your buſineſs is done, but where's <hi>Roſe's</hi> thanks?</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Mer.</speaker>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Roſe,</hi> I, Gad, I ne're dream't o'that; faith, <hi>Roſe,</hi> thou and I'le empty a Bottle ſometimes when thy Miſtreſs is in Bed, ſince thou'rt ſo good at Drinking.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>No, good Sir, <hi>Roſe</hi> is to ſet up in a better Imployment; for now <hi>Ruffle</hi> hath got my Old Miſtreſs, <hi>Roſe</hi> ſhall ſucceed in her place.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>I got his Miſtreſs, don't believe him, Dear, I ne're kept Miſs in my Life.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Sir, 'tis even ſo, but I give her to you freely; ſhe was true to me, and may prove ſo to you.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>How, Marryed to a Wench.</p>
               </sp>
               <pb n="74" facs="tcp:101839:40"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ful.</speaker>
                  <p>Joy be with you, Valiant Sir; ha, ha.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Send you comfort of your Virtuous Lady; ha, ha.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>Shall theſe Rogues laugh they cheated me of above three<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcore pounds to Night already? Make e'm repay me that ſum, I'le forgive all.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Much.</speaker>
                  <p>We'l Dine together, and they ſhall pay the Reckoning.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Breef.</speaker>
                  <p>Good Sir, las, tis all we have to truſt to.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Ruff.</speaker>
                  <p>No grumbling, Raſcals, if you do, I'le ſwinge you: But, Gentlemen, be tender of my Honour, and I'le take all; ſay no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing, I'le to my Eſtate in the Countrey, where I ſhall paſs for as Valiant a Squire, and my Wife for as Virtuous a Lady as the beſt there.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>Well reſolv'd on, and I aſſure you I'le not Viſit your La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy when you are from Home, <hi>Roſe</hi> and I will keep cloſe together.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Hon.</speaker>
                  <p>But, <hi>Roſe,</hi> I hope you don't mean to take ſuch courſes.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Roſe.</speaker>
                  <p>No, Madam, you may be ſure on't, Mr. <hi>Townlove's</hi> merry, and talks wildly, that's all; if he and I keep Company, it ſhall be meerly in Friendſhip; I would not for the World loſe my Reputa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion with him, I hope you have all better thoughts of me.</p>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>Town.</speaker>
                  <p>No, <hi>Roſe,</hi> I'le warrant e'm thee and I will ſecure one ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers Reputations.</p>
                  <p>For want of Cuſtom wonder doth produce,</p>
                  <p>And ills do loſe that Name by frequent uſe.</p>
               </sp>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="epilogue">
            <pb facs="tcp:101839:40"/>
            <head>EPILOGUE.</head>
            <l>POets we juſtly may Wit's Babbles call;</l>
            <l>For they to almoſt nothing venture all.</l>
            <l>They with each Play their Reputations ſtake,</l>
            <l>And ten to one, if good, it doth not take.</l>
            <l>In thoſe that do, that part you onely praiſe,</l>
            <l>Which Comedians mimickry doth raiſe;</l>
            <l>So he, and not the Poet, gets the Bays.</l>
            <l>But if by Chance ſome Writer does Extort</l>
            <l>From the World's Vogue a pretty good Report,</l>
            <l>'Tis ſo allay'd by but why that or this,</l>
            <l>That he might juſtly wiſh 'twas none of his.</l>
            <l>Hard Fate! Have they alone! All men beſide</l>
            <l>Some Curtain ſtill, their faults to hide.</l>
            <l>States-men their Errors on their Agents lay;</l>
            <l>'Tis Chance of War makes Souldiers loſe a Day:</l>
            <l>And your Phyſicians ſhame Death wipes away;</l>
            <l>But every Fool finds faults in every Play.</l>
            <l>Things being ſo, it cannot be deny'd,</l>
            <l>But to be Poet is a man's blind ſide.</l>
            <l>This is the cauſe why Active times produce</l>
            <l>The feweſt Writers for the Stages Uſe.</l>
            <l>The World is buſie now; and ſome dare ſay</l>
            <l>We have not ſeen of late one good New Play.</l>
            <l>And ſuch believe <hi>Shakeſpear,</hi> long ſince in's Grave,</l>
            <l>In Choiceſt Lybraries a place will have.</l>
            <l>When not a modern Play will ſcape the fire:</l>
            <l>I beg their pardons who themſelves admire.</l>
            <l>Not but this Age hath many men as Wiſe,</l>
            <l>But wiſely they this begging Art deſpiſe.</l>
            <l>And two to one, was he alive this Day,</l>
            <l>He'd have more wit, then e're to write a Play.</l>
            <l>His Fruitful Brain would find Employment now,</l>
            <l>Which Times of drowſie Peace did not allow;</l>
            <pb facs="tcp:101839:41"/>
            <l>Then that you write not too, pray think your Eate,</l>
            <l>Good lucky Poets, of your Sword and State:</l>
            <l>And be not too ſevere on thoſe that do,</l>
            <l>For all you Play hath it's Spectators too.</l>
            <l>'Mongſt which there's ſome are Fools enough to blame</l>
            <l>Our preſent War, the greateſt Scene of Fame.</l>
            <l>The beſt contriv'd, beſt lead, and braveſt fought</l>
            <l>Of all, in which <hi>England</hi> has Glory ſought.</l>
            <l>Yet if Croſs Winds, or Storms do make you miſs</l>
            <l>One Action, ſtrait Fanatick Criticks hiſs.</l>
            <l>An Envious ſort of Sots, like ours i'th' Pit;</l>
            <l>Who having none, ſtill rail at all have Wit.</l>
            <l>Our Author, though, is ſafe, and fears e'm not,</l>
            <l>His Play pretends neither to Wit nor Plot;</l>
            <l>But ſhould you Damn it with your utmoſt ſpight,</l>
            <l>When next he's idle, he again will Write.</l>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
